<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>
<item>
  <id>0</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Bob Dylan</name>
  <img>bob</img>
  <bdate>May 24, 1941, Duluth, Minnesota, United States</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>A hero is someone who understands the responsibility that comes with his freedom.</quote>
  <info>
		Bob Dylan is an American singer-songwriter, artist, and writer. He has been an influential figure in popular music and culture for more than five decades. Much of his most celebrated work dates from the 1960s, when he was both a chronicler and a reluctant figurehead of social unrest. A number of Dylan's early songs, such as "Blowin' in the Wind" and "The Times They Are a-Changin'", became anthems for the American civil rights and anti-war movements. Leaving behind his initial base in the culture of the folk music revival, Dylan's six-minute single "Like a Rolling Stone" radically altered the parameters of popular music in 1965. His mid-1960s recordings, backed by rock musicians, reached the top end of the United States music charts while also attracting denunciation and criticism from others in the folk movement.

		Dylan's lyrics have incorporated a variety of political, social, philosophical, and literary influences. They defied existing pop music conventions and appealed hugely to the then burgeoning counterculture. Initially inspired by the performance style of Little Richard, and the songwriting of Woody Guthrie, Robert Johnson, and Hank Williams, Dylan has both amplified and personalized musical genres. His recording career, spanning fifty years, has explored many of the traditions in American song—from folk, blues, and country to gospel, rock and roll, and rockabilly to English, Scottish, and Irish folk music, embracing even jazz and swing. Dylan performs with guitar, keyboards, and harmonica. Backed by a changing line-up of musicians, he has toured steadily since the late 1980s on what has been dubbed the Never Ending Tour. His accomplishments as a recording artist and performer have been central to his career, but his greatest contribution is generally considered his songwriting.

		Since 1994, Dylan has published six books of drawings and paintings, and his work has been exhibited in major art galleries. As a musician, Dylan has sold more than 100 million records worldwide, making him one of the best-selling artists of all time; he has received numerous awards including Grammy, Golden Globe, and Academy Award; he has been inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, Minnesota Music Hall of Fame, Nashville Songwriters Hall of Fame, and Songwriters Hall of Fame. The Pulitzer Prize jury in 2008 awarded him a special citation for "his profound impact on popular music and American culture, marked by lyrical compositions of extraordinary poetic power." In May 2012, Dylan received the Presidential Medal of Freedom from President Barack Obama.

 </info>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VWgJzOzbKQ4</video>
  <achievements>
		Dylan has won many awards throughout his career including 11 Grammy Awards, one Academy Award and one Golden Globe Award; He has been inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, Nashville Songwriters Hall of Fame, and Songwriters Hall of Fame. In May 2000, Dylan was awarded the Polar Music Prize. He received the Presidential Medal of Freedom in May 2012.
  </achievements>
  <video_id>4gWCiLexilY</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Gordon Matthew Thomas Sumner(Sting)</name>
  <img>sting</img>
  <bdate>October, 2 1951, Wallsend, Northumberland, England</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>One of the rewards of success is freedom, the ability to do whatever you like.</quote>
  <info>
		Gordon Matthew Thomas Sumner (born October 2, 1951), better known as Sting, is an English singer and musician. He first became famous as a member of the band, The Police.

		Sting was born in Newcastle, England in 1951 where he attended St. Cuthbert’s Catholic High School. His father was a milkman in an area dominated by the ship building industry. From an early age, Sting displayed an aptitude and love for music, in particular the bass guitar. He sought to pursue a career in music, and took part in a variety of local gigs and gained some employment on cruises.

		His early groups included a mixture of jazz and rock groups such as “Last Exit”

		He received his name Sting from a black and gold striped rugby sweater he used to often wear when performing in a Dixieland jazz band, in which people said he looked like a bee.

		His big break through came with the rock band Police. In 1978, he moved to London where, with Stewart Copeland and Andy Summers, they formed a group ‘The Police’. They went onto sell many best-selling albums and won six Grammy awards. The song ‘Every Breath You Take’ from their last album ‘Synchronicity’ is one of the most played songs on the radio of all time.

		In 1985, he released his first solo ‘The Dream of the Blue Turtles’. This led on to a very successful solo career. The group Police have only sporadically re-united to play charity gigs and the odd tour (2007).

		Sting has experimented with a variety of music from classical to rock and jazz. To Sting music doesn’t have to fit into neat boundaries.

  </info>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qyuEVJc6ndY</video>
  <achievements>
		In 2000, Sting had a star unveiled on the Hollywood Walk of Fame.
	
		In the Queen's Birthday Honours 2003 Sting was appointed a Commander of The Most Excellent Order of the British Empire For services to the Music Industry.

		In 2007, the French Government appointed Sting (along with Police bandmates Andy Summers and Stewart Copeland) a Chevalier of the Ordre des Arts et des Lettres.

		Sting was honored by the Upright Citizens Brigade team, Fambly, in the form of a 30-minute sketch comedy show devoted to the 1999 song "Brand New Day". He was formally invited to the encore performance of the show, held at the theatre on November 7, 2011.

  </achievements>
  <video_id>4gWCiLexilY</video_id> 
 </item>

<item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Ravi Shankar</name>
  <img>ravishankar</img>
  <bdate>April 7, 1920, Varanasi, India</bdate>
  <ddate>December 11, 2012, La Jolla, San Diego, California, United States</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Pop changes week to week, month to month. But great music is like literature.</quote>
  <info>Ravi Shankar is a legendary sitar player and one of India's most esteemed classical musicians. Pandit Ravi Shankar has made a major contribution in popularizing Indian classical music in the West through his association with The Beatles (especially George Harrison). 

		Pandit Ravi Shankar was born on April 7, 1920 at Varanasi, India. His elder brother Uday Shankar was a famous Indian classical dancer. In his early years Ravi Shankar joined his elder brother, Uday Shankar and his troupe and went to Paris in 1930 to experiment with the stage by playing small roles in ballets for the next three years. 

		In 1938, Ravi Shankar gave up a possible dance career and started learning sitar under Allauddin Khan, founder of the Maihar Gharana of Indian classical music. Ravi Shankar's formal training ended in 1944. Thereafter, Pandit Ravi Shankar joined the IPTA and composed music for several ballets, started Renaissance artistes in 1947 and was in charge of Vadya Vrinda at the All India Radio in 1949. Ravi Shankar first performed outside India in the Soviet Union in 1954. He also performed at major events such as the Edinburgh Festival as well as major venues such as Royal Festival Hall. In 1960s, Ravi Shankar's fusion with George Harrison, a member of The Beatles became very popular in the US and helped in popularizing Indian classical music in the West.

		Pandit Ravi Shankar has won several honours and awards. These include: Padma Vibhushan, Magsaysay Award, two Grammy Awards, Fukuoka Grand Prize from Japan, and the Crystal Award from Davos. In 1999, Ravi Shankar was awarded with Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian honour. He was also a nominated member of the Rajya Sabha, India's upper house of Parliament, from 1986 to 1992.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4gWCiLexilY</video>
  <achievements>
		Ravi Shankar is a legendary sitar player and one of India's most esteemed classical musicians. Pandit Ravi Shankar has made a major contribution in popularizing Indian classical music in the West through his association with The Beatles (especially George Harrison). 

		Made a major contribution in popularizing Indian classical music in the West; Recipient of Padma Vibhushan, Magsaysay Award, AND two Grammy Awards. 
  </achievements>
  <video_id>4gWCiLexilY</video_id> 
 </item>

<item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>William Shakespeare</name>
  <img>shakespeare</img>
  <bdate>April 26, 1564, Stratford-upon-Avon, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>April 23, 1616, Stratford-upon-Avon, United Kingdom</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Love all, trust a few, do wrong to none.</quote>
  <info>William Shakespeare was baptized on 26 April 1564. We don't know the exact date of his birth but in the 16th century it was normal for babies to baptized within a few days of their birth (because so many died). Shakespeare was born the same year as Christopher Marlowe.

		William Shakespeare's father John was a glover (maker of gloves) and he seems to have been a leading citizen of Stratford Upon Avon.

		We don't know if John Shakespeare was a native of Stratford but he was living in the town by 1552 because in that year he was fined for leaving a dunghill in Henley Street. At that time Stratford was a small town with a population of between 1,500 and 2,000.
		In 1557 John Shakespeare married a woman from nearby Wilmcote called Mary Arden. The Shakespeares had 8 children. In 1558 the Shakespeare's had a daughter called Joan (she died in 1563). However in 1563 they had another daughter called Margaret but she too died in childhood. After William in 1563 they had a son called Gilbert in 1566. (He died in 1612). They also had another daughter called Joan (like her dead sister) in 1569 and a daughter called Anne in 1571. In 1574 they had a son called Richard (he died in 1613). In 1580 they had a son called Edmund (he died in 1607).

		When he was 18 William Shakespeare married a woman named Anne Hathaway. They married in November 1582 and their daughter Susanna was baptized in May 1583.

		On 2 February 1585 the Shakespeare's next children, a twin boy and girl, Hamnet and Judith were baptized. However Hamnet died when he was 11.

		William Shakespeare probably went to Stratford Grammar School. However we do not know what he did for a living when he was a young man but in about 1587 he went to London. He became an actor and a playwright.

		By 1592 William Shakespeare was making a name for himself. In that year a man named Robert Greene wrote about 'an upstart crow' who 'is in his own conceit the only Shake-scene in a country. He didn't actually name William Shakespeare but it is clear who he meant.

		The theatres in London were closed from 1592 to 1594 because of plague but Shakespeare wrote two poems during that time, Venus and Adonis 1593 and Lucerce in 1594.

		William Shakespeare prospered and in 1597 he bought a house and gardens in Stratford for £60.

		William Shakespeare made his will on 25 March 1616 shortly before he death. He died on 23 April 1616 and was buried in the parish church. Anne Shakespeare died in 1623. Susanna died in 1649 and Judith, the surviving twin died in 1662.

		In the 19th century as Stratford upon Avon became famous as the birthplace of William Shakespeare. The house where he was born was purchased in 1847 and turned into a monument. Anne Hathaway's cottage was purchased in 1892. The Royal Shakespeare Theatre was built in 1932 and the Shakespeare Centre opened in 1964.

		Today William Shakespeare is remembered as one of the greatest English playwrights.
	</info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xc2MQh_GwkQ</video>
  <achievements>
		Throghout his short life, Shakespeare had many great achievements. Altogether, he wrote 154 sonnets, 38 plays and 2 narratives. His most famous plays include Romeo and Juliet, A Midsummer Nights Dream, Hamlet and Macbeth.He wrote tradgedies and comedies, and histories.
  
		Since the 19th century, Shakespeare's achievements have been more consistently recognized, and throughout the Western world he has come to be regarded as the greatest dramatist ever.
 
		One of Shakespeare's most renown plays would probably be Romeo and Juliet. Everyone knows of the undeniable love between the two lovers, of the tragic story of two people who want nothing more than to see each other only to be thwarted by their family.
  </achievements>
  <video_id>xc2MQh_GwkQ</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Ali Akbar Khan</name>
  <img>aliakbarkhan</img>
  <bdate>April 14, 1922, Comilla, Bangladesh</bdate>
  <ddate>June 18, 2009, San Anselmo, California, United States</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Real music is not for wealth, not for honours or even the joys of the mind... but as a path for realisation and salvation.</quote>
  <info>Ustad Ali Akbar Khan was one of the most accomplished Indian classical musicians, admired all over the world for his brilliant compositions and his mastery of the sarode. Ustad Ali Akbar Khan is considered by many as the "Indian Johann Sebastian Bach."

		Ali Akbar Khan was born on April 14, 1922 in East Bengal (Bangladesh). His family traces its gharana (ancestral tradition) to Mian Tansen, a 16th century musical genius and court musician of Emperor Akbar. Khan's father, the late Padma Vibhusan Acharya Dr. Allauddin Khan, was regarded as the greatest figure in North Indian music in 20th century. Khan started learning music at the age of three. He learnt vocal music from his father and drums from his uncle, Fakir Aftabuddin. He learnt how to play several other musical instruments too, but finally decided to concentrate on the sarode and vocal. 

		Khan gave his first public performance in Allahabad, at the age of thirteen. In his early twenties, he made his first recording in Lucknow, for the HMV label. The next year, he became the court musician to the Maharaja of Jodhpur. He worked there for seven years and the state of Jodhpur bestowed upon him the title of Ustad. Several years later (1993), Ustad Ali Akbar Khan received the title of Hathi Saropao and Dowari Tajeem, at Jodhpur Palace's Golden Jubilee Celebration.

		Khan first visited the United States in 1955, on the request of Lord Menuhin and gave a memorable concert at the Museum of Modern Art in New York. He played a major role in popularizing Indian classical music in the US. He also founded the Ali Akbar College of Music in Calcutta, India, in the year 1956. Khan began teaching music in America in 1965. Later, he founded the Ali Akbar College of Music, in Marin County, California.

		Ustad Ali Akbar Khan gave music in several films. These include: "Aandhiyan" by Chetan Anand (1953), "House Holder" by Ivory/Merchant, "Khudita Pashan" (for which he won the "Best Musician of the Year" Award), "Devi" by Satyajit Ray, and "Little Buddha" by Bernardo Bertolucci. In 1997, he was chosen for the Asian Paints Shiromani Award - Hall of Fame. He was the second recipient of the award, after Satyajit Ray.

		Ustad Ali Akbar Khan left for the holy abode on June 19, 2009, in San Francisco (United States Of America), after suffering from a kidney ailment for quite sometime. He was on dialysis and his condition had deteriorated in the last four months preceding his death. He breathed his last at his music centre, at the age of 88. The Sarod maestro is survived by his wife Mary and eleven children, apart from his musical legacy that includes the Ali Akbar College of Music in San Rafael, California.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r17LmpFCAFQ</video> 
  <video_id>r17LmpFCAFQ</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Ustad Ali Akbar Khan was one of the most accomplished Indian classical musicians, admired all over the world for his brilliant compositions and his mastery of the sarode. Ustad Ali Akbar Khan is considered by many as the "Indian Johann Sebastian Bach."

		Popularized Indian classical music in the West; Recipient of the Asian Paints Shiromani Award.
  </achievements> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>M. S. Subbulakshmi</name>
  <img>mssubbulakshmi</img>
  <bdate>September 16, 1916, Madurai, India</bdate>
  <ddate>December 11, 2004, Chennai, India</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>My greatest fear is giving performances. I feel I am responsible for the audience but I am also scared of them.</quote>
  <info>MS Subbulakshmi was a legendary Carnatic musician. She was popularly known as Nightingale of India. Her rendering of bhajans (devotional songs) was divine and used to enthrall and transfix listeners, and transport them into a different world

		MS Subbulakshmi (Madurai Shanmukhavadivu Subbulakshmi) was born as Kunjamma in the temple city of Madurai on September 16, 1916. She was born into a family of musicians. Her grandmother Akkammal played the violin and her mother was a veena artist. 

		MS Subbulakshmi started learning Carnatic music from a very early age. She made her debut as a singer at the age of eight and went on to perform in concerts, a domain traditionally reserved for males. She began her Carnatic classical music training under Semmangudi Srinivasa Iyer and then Hindustani classical training under Pandit Narayan Rao Vyas.

		By the age of 17, Subbulakshmi was giving concerts on her own, including major performances at the Madras Music Academy, the prestigious center for the study and promotion of Carnatic music. In 1940, she married T. Sadasivam, a freedom fighter, and a follower of Rajaji. He played a key role in advancing her career.

		She also acted in a few Tamil films in her youth. Her first movie "Sevasadanam" was released in 1938. MS Subbulakshmi also played the male role of Narada in "Savitri" (1941) to raise money for launching Kalki, her husband's nationalist Tamil weekly. Her title role of the Rajasthani saint-poetess Meera in the eponymous film (1945) gave her national prominence. This movie was re-made in Hindi in 1947. The movie had M.S Subbulakshmi. sing the famous Meera bhajans, with Dilipkumar Roy as the music director. Those renditions by M.S. continue to haunt listeners to this day. Following the success of the film she quit films and turned wholly to concert music.

		MS Subbulakshmi traveled to London, New York, Canada, the Far East, and other places as India's cultural ambassador. Her concerts at Carnegie Hall, New York; the UN General Assembly on UN day in 1966; the Royal Albert Hall, London in 1982; and at the Festival of India in Moscow in 1987 were significant landmarks in her career. 

		MS Subbulakshmi received many honours and awards. These include Padma Bhushan in 1954, Sangeetha Kalanidhi in 1968 (She was the first woman recipient of the title), Ramon Magsaysay award in 1974, the Padma Vibhushan in 1975, the Kalidasa Samman in 1988, the Indira Gandhi Award for National Integration in 1990, and the Bharat Ratna in 1998. She was also honored as the court-singer of Tirumala Tirupati Devasthanams.

		After the death of her husband Sadasivam in 1997, MS Subbulakshmi stopped all her public performances. She had no children. MS Subbulakshmi died on December 11, 2004 after a brief illness.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lGuuavo2JHU</video>
  <video_id>lGuuavo2JHU</video_id> 
  <achievements>
		MS subbulakshmi was received many awards and honours. She was honored with padma bhushan award in 1954. She was achieved awards like Sangget Natak Academy in 1956 and Sangeetha Kalanidhi in 1968(she was the first women for this award). And she was got Ramon Magsaysay award in 1974, the Padma Vibhushan in 1975, the Kalidas Samman in 1988, the Indira Gandhi Award for National Integration in 1990, and the Bharat Ratna in 1998. She was honored as a singer of Tirumala Tirupati Devasthanams.

		MS Subbalakshmi called with different names like Tapaswini, Suswaralakshmi and Aathuvaan Sur.

		MS subbalakshmi Bhajans and songs.

		Some of her most famous bhajans are Bhaja Govindam, Vishnu sahasranama, Venkateswara Suprabhatam.
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>6</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>John Lennon</name>
  <img>john</img>
  <bdate>October 9, 1940, Liverpool, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>December 8, 1980, New York City, New York, United States</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>You don't need anybody to tell you who you are or what you are. You are what you are!</quote>
  <info>
		John Ono Lennon,was an English musician, singer and songwriter who rose to worldwide fame as a founder member of the rock band the Beatles, the most commercially successful band in the history of popular music. With Paul McCartney, he formed a songwriting partnership that is one of the most celebrated of the 20th century.

		Born and raised in Liverpool, as a teenager Lennon became involved in the skiffle craze; his first band, the Quarrymen, evolved into the Beatles in 1960. When the group disbanded in 1970, Lennon embarked on a solo career that produced the critically acclaimed albums John Lennon/Plastic Ono Band and Imagine, and iconic songs such as "Give Peace a Chance" and "Working Class Hero". After his marriage to Yoko Ono in 1969, he changed his name to John Ono Lennon. Lennon disengaged himself from the music business in 1975 to raise his infant son Sean, but re-emerged with Ono in 1980 with the new album Double Fantasy. He was murdered three weeks after its release.

		Lennon revealed a rebellious nature and acerbic wit in his music, writing, drawings, on film and in interviews. Controversial through his political and peace activism, he moved to Manhattan in 1971, where his criticism of the Vietnam War resulted in a lengthy attempt by Richard Nixon's administration to deport him, while some of his songs were adopted as anthems by the anti-war movement and the larger counterculture.

		As of 2012, Lennon's solo album sales in the United States exceeded 14 million and, as writer, co-writer or performer, he is responsible for 25 number-one singles on the US Hot 100 chart. In 2002, a BBC poll on the 100 Greatest Britons voted him eighth and, in 2008, Rolling Stone ranked him the fifth-greatest singer of all time. He was posthumously inducted into the Songwriters Hall of Fame in 1987 and into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 1994.

	</info>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hhSWmPVcWfg</video>
  <video_id>TMpRu8yYjTA</video_id>
  <achievements>
		1971 Won Oscar Best Music, Original Song Score 
		Let It Be (1970)
		The Beatles were not present at the awards ceremony. Quincy Jones accepted the award on their behalf. 


		BAFTA Awards 
		1965 Nominated BAFTA Film Award Most Promising Newcomer to Leading Film Roles for: A Hard Day's Night (1964) 


		BMI Film and TV Awards 
		2003 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Providence" (1999) 
		2002 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Providence" (1999) 
		2000 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Providence" (1999) 

		1999 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Providence" (1999) 
		1996 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Grace Under Fire" (1993) 
		1995 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Grace Under Fire" (1993) 
		1994 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "Grace Under Fire" (1993) 
		1990 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "The Wonder Years" (1988) 
		1989 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "The Wonder Years" (1988) 
		1988 Won BMI TV Music Award for: "The Wonder Years" (1988) 
		
		Grammy Awards 
		1997 Won Grammy Best Music Video - Long Form for: "The Beatles Anthology" (1995) (mini) 
		1971 Won Grammy Best Original Score Written for a Motion Picture or Television Special for: Let It Be (1970) 
		1970 Nominated Grammy Best Original Score Written for a Motion Picture or Television Show for: Yellow Submarine (1968) 
		1966 Nominated Grammy Best Original Score Written for a Motion Picture or Television Show for: Help! (1965) 
		1965 Nominated Grammy Best Original Score Written for a Motion Picture or Television Show 
		
		A Hard Day's Night (1964) 
		Laurel Awards 
		1966 2nd place Golden Laurel Musical Performance, Male 
		
  </achievements>  
 </item>
 
<item>
  <id>7</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Bhimsen Joshi</name>
  <img>new_bhimsen</img>
  <bdate>February 4, 1922, Gadag-Betageri, India</bdate>
  <ddate>January 24, 2011, Pune,  India</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Had I not been a singer, I would have loved to spend my entire life in a garage fine-tuning a Fiat or a Maruti.</quote>
  <info>One of the most prominent and legendary Hindustani vocalist living today is of course Pandit Bhimsen Joshi. He can very easily be called a living legend and someone who has not just earned true fans but has also won over critics. Born on 4th February, 1922 in Karnataka, Pandit Bhimsen Joshi is the descendant of Kirana stream of Hindustani classical music. He is famous for the "Khayal", a form of Hindustani classical. Bhimsen Joshi was interested in music since a very young age and at the age of 11 he left home in search of a Guru. Read the fascinating life history of Pt. Bhimsen Joshi in this short biography. 

		He found the apt teacher for him very close to his house. Under the tutelage of Savai Gandharva he learnt many ragas and perfected his tone, pitch and the best of Kirana gharana. His sheer determination and hard work has made him what he is today. In the last five decades, his popularity has increased manifold because of the intensity and passion he brings in his songs. Other concert artists truly appreciate his style and the passion that he gets into his songs. His first public performance was at the age of 19. 

		Bhimsen Joshi has perfected not just the Khayal interpretations but has also sung Bhajans in Hindi and Marathi. His bhajans are widely heard by not just ardent music lovers but people all over. This versatile singer has also recorded Kannada Dasa Krithis in Dasavani, which are usually sung by Carnatic musicians. His sheer grit and determination earned him his first Platinum Disc in 1986. He has also been presented the Padma Shree in 1972, the Sangeet Natak Akademi Award in 1976 and the Padma Bhushan in 1985. Perhaps some of his best performances have been at Savai Gandharva Sangeet Mahotsav, which is held in Pune annually. It has been a regular feature since the past 3 decades and has become an institution of sorts. 

		His most memorable performance that is remembered till date is of course the national integration song "Mile Sur Mera Tumhara". His golden voice appealing to Indians to come together and stand as one nation is an evergreen number that is hummed by one and all even today. He has collaborated with many other renowned musicians like Hariprasad Chaurasiya, Pandit Ravi Shankar and Dr. Balamuralikrishna and has come out with many albums. He is a living legend who continues to weave magic with his unique voice even today.
	</info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TMpRu8yYjTA</video>
  <video_id>TMpRu8yYjTA</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Pandit Bhimsen Joshi was the numero uno amongst Hindustani classical vocalists. He was considered as the leading light of the Kirana gharana. Bhimsen Joshi is renowned for his unique style and mastery over ragas. 

		1971-Padma Shree
		1976- Sangeet Natak Akademi Award
		1985- Padma Bhushan
		1985- National Award For Best Playback Singer
		1999- Padma Vibhushan
		2002- Maharashtra Bhushan
		2005- Karnataka Ratna
		2008- Bharat Ratna
		2009- Lifetime Achievement Award by Delhi Government
		'Swathi Sangeet Puraskaram' by The Government of Kerala
  </achievements>  
 </item>
 
 
 <item>
  <id>8</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Paul Potts</name>
  <img>paul</img>
  <bdate>October 13, 1970, Kingswood, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>When boys and girls go out to play there is always someone left behind, and the boy who is left behind is no use to the girl who is left behind.</quote>
  <info>
		Paul Robert Potts is a British singer. In 2007, he won the first series of ITV's Britain's Got Talent with his performance of "Nessun dorma", an aria from Puccini's opera Turandot. As a singer of operatic pop music, Potts recorded the album One Chance, which topped sales charts in nine countries. Prior to winning Britain's Got Talent, Potts was a manager at The Carphone Warehouse. He had served as Bristol city councilor from 1996 until 2003, and also had performed in amateur opera from 1999 to 2003.

		Potts was born in Kingswood and raised in nearby Fishponds by his father Roland, a bus driver, and mother, Yvonne (née Higgins), a supermarket cashier. He has two brothers and one sister.

		Potts attended St Mary Redcliffe and Temple School, where he developed his love of singing. He also sang with the choir at Chester Park Junior School and with the choirs at several Bristol churches, including Christ Church. Potts said in interviews that he had been bullied in school, and that experience may have made him lack self-confidence. He has also said that his voice had always been a source of solace in the past when he was bullied.

		After he left school in 1987 Potts had various jobs including working at Waitrose and Tesco; he also worked part-time at Debenhams.

		In 1993 Potts earned a B.A. (Bachelor of Arts) Honours degree in Humanities from University College Plymouth St Mark and St John. In 1996, Potts was elected the youngest member of Bristol City Council; a Liberal Democrat, he served until 2003. Potts was a manager at mobile phone store Carphone Warehouse in Bridgend, Wales, and lived in Port Talbot. Potts took singing lessons in Italy, but the expense meant that he was forced to give them up.

		After winning Britain's Got Talent, Potts took a six-month sabbatical from his job and resigned on 5 March 2008.
		
   </info>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1k08yxu57NA</video>
  <video_id>TMpRu8yYjTA</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Got nomination for World Music Award
		category World's Best Classical Artist 
  </achievements>  
 </item>
 
  <item>
  <id>9</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Lata Mangeshkar</name>
  <img>latamangeshkar</img>
  <bdate>September 28, 1929 (age 85), Indore, India</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>I have decided that I won't take up assignments that don't interest me.</quote>
  <info>Lata Mangeshkar is one of the best singers of the Hindi film industry. She is listed in the Guinness Book of World Records as the most recorded artist in the world. It is estimated that she has more than 30,000 solo, duet and chorus backed songs in 20 different languages from 1948 to 1987. Now, it must way over 40,000! Lata Mangeshkar was born on 28th September, 1929 in a place called Indore. Her father Dinanath Mangeshkar was a renowned classical singer himself. Lata was introduced to music at a very young age. The life history of Lata Mangeshkar is truly fascinating. Read this short biography of Lata Mungeshkar. 

		Lata Mangeshkar was very young when her father passed away, thus making the family dependant on Lata. To take care of her family's economic situation, Lata acted in as many as 8 films from 1942 to 1948. She debuted as playback singer in a Marathi film named Kiti Hasaal (1942). Unfortunately the song was edited out. Her first Hindi playback was for the film Aap ke Sewa Main (1947) but she did not get noticed. At that time, the film industry was ruled by female singers who had heavier and huskier voices like Noor Jehan, Shamshad Begum and Zohrabai Ambalewali. While auditioning for the movie Shaheed (1948), she was rejected on the account of her thin voice! But Ghulam Haider saw the potential in her and gave her a chance to sing in the film Majboor. 

		The song Dil Mera Toda finally got her noticed and it was touted as her breakthrough song. In 1949, she had four major hits from the films Barsaat, Andaaz, Dulari and Mahal. The song "Aayega Aanewala" from Mahal was a huge hit and Lata secured a firm position in the industry. The husky voices of all other singers became obsolete in front of the high pitched voice of Lata Mangeshkar. The music industry had a huge makeover with the arrival of Lata Mangeshkar. By the late 50's, the younger sister of Lata Mangeshkar known as Asha Bhonsle also came into the scene and they both were touted as the unbeatable voices of the industry. 

		Lata rose to fame rapidly and made her indelible mark in the industry. She has sung with famous singers like Mohammed Rafi, Kishore Kumar, Mukesh, etc. She has perfected almost every genre of music. Her success and determination made her one of the most powerful women in the industry. She refused to sing for the great composer S.D Burman due to some misunderstanding and also stopped singing with Mohammed Rafi. Her power was so immense that they had to come back to her. She actually monopolized the music industry and every music director wanted to work with her. She understood the requirement of each song and sang flawlessly. 

		Lata Mangeshkar has been honored with innumerable awards but the one that truly deserves a special mention is that she is the only second singer in the non-classical category (after M.S Subbulakshmi) in India to have received the highest civilian award, Bharat Ratna. She has received three national awards and eight Filmfare awards after which she stopped accepting awards in order to promote new talent. She continues to sing every now and then for Hindi movies and perform live. Truly a living legend, Lata Mangeshkar has a talent that is second to none.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ou0B9T89L0g</video>
  <video_id>Ou0B9T89L0g</video_id> 
  <achievements>
		Filmfare Awards (1958, 1962, 1965, 1969, 1993 and 1994)
		National Awards (1972, 1975 and 1990)
		Maharashtra State Award (1966 and 1967)
		1969 - Padma Bhushan 
		1974 - Recorded in the Guinness Book of World Records for having sung the maximum number of songs in the world 
		1989 - Dada Saheb Phalke Award
		1993 - Filmfare Lifetime Achievement Award 
		1996 - Star Screen Lifetime Achievement Award 
		1997 - Rajiv Gandhi Award 
		1999 - NTR Award 
		1999 - Padma Vibhushan 
		1999 - Zee Cine Award for Lifetime Achievement 
		2000 - Lifetime Achievement Award by IIFA in London 
		2001 - Best Playback Singer of the Millennium (female) by Hero Honda and magazine "Stardust"
		2001 - Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian award
		2001 - Noorjehan Award 
		2001 - Maharashtra Ratna
  </achievements>  
 </item>
 
  <item>
  <id>10</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>William Hung</name>
  <img>williamhung</img>
  <bdate>January 13, 1983</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Whatever you believe in, and if you keep trying, you can eventually succeed.</quote>
  <info>William Hung became famous by performing badly in a televised audition for the talent show American Idol. Hung's tone-deaf performance of the Ricky Martin tune "She Bangs" was greeted with sneers by judge Simon Cowell, but Hung's plucky reply became famous: "I already gave my best, and I have no regrets at all." Video of his comically clumsy dance moves began circulating on the Internet early in 2004 and Hung grew into a public phenomenon. He went along with the gag and began accepting invitations to perform "She Bangs" at Cal events, then on TV talk shows and even in concerts nationwide, often with a backing chorus of dancing girls. It was never quite clear if fans were mocking Hung's lack of talent or saluting his cheerful persistence, and Hung himself has continued to insist that he wants to pursue a career in music. His album Inspiration debuted at #34 on the Billboard album charts upon its release in April of 2004.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9RrLQUN8UJg</video>
  <video_id>9RrLQUN8UJg</video_id>
  <achievements>
 		William Hung was offered a $25,000 advance on a record deal from Koch Entertainment in 2004, and released three albums on that label in 2004 and 2005. His first album was titled Inspiration and was produced by Giuseppe D. It was recorded over a March 2004 weekend with Hung singing vocals over karaoke music. To promote it, Hung performed before nearly 20,000 fans during half-time at a Golden State Warriors game on April 6 and performed "She Bangs", included on the album, on such shows as The Tonight Show with Jay Leno. The album received highly negative reviews, but ultimately went on to sell about 200,000 copies and reached Number One on Billboard's Top Independent Album Chart. His two follow-up albums were far less successful, as Hung for the Holidays (a Christmas album) only sold 35,000 copies and Miracle: Happy Summer from William Hung (another karaoke cover album) only sold 7,000. In a February 2006 interview, he said he was working on a 5 or 6-track fourth album,though with his retirement in 2011, it is not likely such an album will ever be released.
  </achievements> 
 </item>
 
<item>
  <id>11</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Zakir Hussain</name>
  <img>zakirhussain</img>
  <bdate>March 9, 1951, Mumbai</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>There's drums, there's rhythm, there's dance, there's song. All these come together in hopefully one balanced and very cohesive performance.</quote>
  <info>Zakir Hussain is a classical tabla virtuoso and the most famous tabla player in India today. His contribution in the field of percussion and in the music world at large is highly appreciated. 

		Ustad Zakir Hussain was born on March 9, 1951. His father Ustad Allarakha was himself an established tabla player. Zakir Hussain did his schooling from St. Michael's High School in Mahim and completed his graduation from St Xaviers, Mumbai. Zakir Hussain was a child prodigy and started touring by the age of twelve. He came to the United States in 1970 and started his international career. 

		Zakir Hussain is widely considered as the chief architect of the contemporary world music movement. He founded much historic collaboration. These include: Shakti, which he founded with John McLaughlin and L. Shankar, the Diga Rhythm Band, Making Music, Planet Drum with Mickey Hart, and recordings and performances with a number of artists such as George Harrison, Joe Henderson, Van Morrison, Jack Bruce, Tito Puente, Pharoah Sanders, Billy Cobham, the Hong Kong Symphony and the New Orleans Symphony. 

		In 1987, Zakir Hussain's first solo release, "Making Music," was acclaimed as "one of the most inspired East-West fusion albums ever recorded." In 1988, Zakir Hussain became the youngest percussionist to ever be awarded the title of "Padma Shri" by the Indian government. In 1990, he was awarded the Indo-American Award in recognition for his outstanding cultural contribution to relations between the United States and India. In April, 1991, Zakir Hussain was presented with the Sangeet Natak Akademi Award by the President of India. Zakir Hussain is also the recipient of the 1999 National Heritage Fellowship, the United States' most prestigious honor for a master in the traditional arts.

		Zakir Hussain has composed soundtracks for several movies, notable among them are "In Custody" and "The Mystic Masseur" by Ismail Merchant. Zakir Hussain has also played tabla on the soundtracks of Francis Coppola's "Apocalypse Now", Bernardo Bertolucci's "Little Buddha".

  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=As1OMMcHXFs</video>
  <video_id>As1OMMcHXFs</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Zakir Hussain is a classical tabla virtuoso and the most famous tabla player in India today. His contribution in the field of percussion and in the music world at large is highly appreciated. 
 
		Considered as the chief architect of the contemporary world music movement; youngest percussionist to ever be awarded the title of Padma Shri 

		He not only founded Jamia Milia Islamia University but served as its Vice Chancellor as well. He has contributed so much to the institution that the history of the two has become inseparable and identical  
  </achievements> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>12</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Michael Jackson</name>
  <img>michaeljackson</img>
  <bdate>August 29, 1958, Gary, Indiana, United States</bdate>
  <ddate>June 25, 2009, Holmby Hills, Los Angeles, California, United States</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Let us dream of tomorrow where we can truly love from the soul, and know love as the ultimate truth at the heart of all creation.</quote>
  <info>Michael Jackson was unquestionably the biggest pop star of the '80s, and certainly one of the most popular recording artists of all time. In his prime, Jackson was an unstoppable juggernaut, possessed of all the tools to dominate the charts seemingly at will: an instantly identifiable voice, eye-popping dance moves, stunning musical versatility, and loads of sheer star power. His 1982 blockbuster Thriller became the biggest-selling album of all time (probably his best-known accomplishment), and he was the first black artist to find stardom on MTV, breaking down innumerable boundaries both for his race and for music video as an art form. Yet as Jackson's career began, very gradually, to descend from the dizzying heights of his peak years, most of the media's attention focused on his increasingly bizarre eccentricities; he was often depicted as a man-child in a state of arrested development, completely sheltered from adult reality by a life spent in show business. The snickering turned to scandal in 1993, when Jackson was accused of molesting a 13-year-old boy; although he categorically denied the charges, his out-of-court settlement failed to restore his tarnished image. He never quite escaped the stigma of those allegations, and while he continued to sell records at superstar-like levels, he didn't release them with enough frequency (or, many critics thought, inspiration) to once again become better known for his music than his private life. Whether as a pop icon or a tabloid caricature, Jackson always remained bigger than life.
  
	   In the wake of his death, everyone in the world seemed to talk of his or her favorite Jackson song, or favorite Jackson dance move or favorite Jackson video. I'll never forget that night back in early 1983, when onstage in Pasadena, California, at the Motown 25th anniversary show, Michael Jackson gave his first public performance as a mature artist staking his own claim, vaulting into that astonishingly graceful, electrifying version of "Billie Jean." Dancing, spinning, sending out impassioned, fierce glares at the overcome audience, Jackson did a powerful job of animating and mythologizing his own blend of mystery and sexuality. I'd never seen anything quite like it before. Maybe I never will again. Michael Jackson didn't just grab the gold ring: He hooked it to a new bar and set it even higher, and nobody has yet snatched it with quite the same flair or results.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_4IRMYuE1hI</video>
  <video_id>_4IRMYuE1hI</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Michael Jackson has set many records throughout his career and won many awards. From the early days of the Jackson 5 to the current day. Michael Jackson has been in a league of his own with his best competition being himself and trying to improve on what he has already achieved. 
		He are a just a few of the record breaking achievements. 

		Biggest Selling Album Of All Time - Guiness Book Of World Records
		Michael Jackson's "Thriller" Album is the biggest selling album of all time, with over 50 million copies sold worldwide. Thriller is also the biggest selling U.S album with sales of 25 million copies.

		Most No1 Hits in 1980's
		By The End of the 1980's MIchael Jackson had more #1 hits than any other artist for the decade.

		Greatest Audience - Guiness Book Of World Records
		The highest-ever viewership was 133.4 million viewers watching the NBC transmission of Super Bowl XXVII on June 31, 1993. Michael was spotlighted during the half-time peformance.

		Bad Tour - Guiness Book Of World Records
		Michael Jackson's world tour brought in a record gross revenue of over $124 million during September 1987-December 1988.

		100 Million Records
		Michael has sold over 100 million singles and albums outside of the U.S.

		Billboard Charts
		Michael Jackson is the first person in the 37 year history of the Billboard chart to enter straight in at No1, with his single "You Are Not Alone". The previous record "Earth Song" which had debuted at No5 and also Michael Jacksons.

		Biggest Selling Video
		Michael Jackson's "The Making Of Thriller" is the biggest selling video to be released by an artist.

		Billboard "Hot 100" Singles Chart
		Most No1 Hits by Male Artist (13)

		No1 Debuts
		Michael Jacksons "Bad", "Dangerous", and "HIStory" albums all debuted in at No1.

		Awards
		Michael has won more awards than any other artist.

		No1 On Charts
		In 1983 Michael became the first artist to simultaneously hold the number one spots on Billboard's rock albums and rock singles charts, as well as the R and B albums and singles charts.

		Consecutive No1 Singles
		Jackson 5 were the first group to ever have four consecutive No1 singles.
		
  </achievements> 
 </item>

 <item>
  <id>13</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>A. R. Rahman</name>
  <img>rahman</img>
  <bdate>January 6, 1967, Chennai, India</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Your inner voice is the voice of divinity. To hear it, we need to be in solitude, even in crowded places.</quote>
  <info>Allah Rakha Rahman, who is better known as AR Rahman, is a world-class musician of India. Born as A. S. Dileep Kumar on 6 January 1967 at Chennai in Tamil Nadu, AR Rahman holds the credit for totally overhauling the style in which music was being made in India. Soundtracks and scores composed by him for Indian films have a strong impression of classical, folk, jazz, reggae, soft rock and other genres. Due to his creative brilliance, AR Rahman is often referred to as the Mozart of Madras by his fans in India and abroad. 

		The biography of AR Rahman's career spans somewhere over a decade, but he has already sold over one hundred million records world-wide and more than two hundred million cassettes. This has brought Rahman into the category of the world's top 25 all-time top selling recording artists. Though AR Rahman is the undisputed leader in Indian contemporary music in the present times, he has seen his share of struggle in the professional life.
	
		His father, R K Shekhar, who was a composer, arranger and conductor for Malayalam films died when Rahman was just 9 years-old and his family rented out musical equipment as a source of income. Later there was a turning point when Dileep Kumar decided to rechristen himself as A R Rahman. This incident happened when Rahman's sister was very ill once. A Muslim friend suggested if he prayed in a particular mosque, his sister would recover and so did happen. This caused the entire family to convert to Islam. 

		The life history of AR Rahman's music career started scaling upwards 1991 onwards when began his own studio and started making music for advertisements, television channels and so on. Rahman got his very first break into the Indian film industry when film director, Mani Ratnam offered him a chance to compose music for his Tamil film, Roja at mere Rs 25,000. This movie turned out to be blockbuster hit and then there was no looking back for A.R. Rahman. 

		Roja debut made AR Rahman bag the Rajat Kamal award for best music director at the National Film Awards. This was a historic moment as for the first time ever in Indian film industry, this award was being handed to a first-time film composer. There was no looking back for AR Rahman after this as film offers just started pouring in. There are now an impressive number of music tracks created by Rahman and all of them have sold like hot cakes across India and even abroad. He has made songs for super hit films like Rangeela, Dil Se Taal, Rang De Basanti, Bombay et al.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sp6wUe9gMrw</video>
  <video_id>Sp6wUe9gMrw</video_id> 
  <achievements>
		1995 – Kalaimamani
		Contributions to music awarded by the Government of Tamil Nadu
		1995 – Mauritius National Award
		Contributions to music awarded by Mauritius
		1995 – Malaysian Award
		Contributions to music awarded by Malaysia
		2000 – Padma Shri
		Fourth highest civilian award awarded by Government of India
		2004 – National Lata Mangeshkar Award
		Contributions to music awarded by the Government of Madhya Pradesh
		2005 – Mahavir-Mahatma Award
		2006 – Swaralaya Yesudas Award
		Swaralaya-Kairali-Yesudas Award for outstanding performance in the music field
		2006 – Honorary Award from Stanford University
		2008 – Rotary Club of Madras
		
		2009 – Honorary Doctorate from Anna University
		2009 – Honorary Doctorate from Aligarh University
		2009 – Honorary Doctorate from Middlesex University
		2010 – Padma Bhushan
		Third highest civilian award awarded by Government of India
		
		1993 – National Film Award for Best Music Direction – Roja
		1997 – National Film Award for Best Music Direction – Minsaara Kanavu
		2002 – National Film Award for Best Music Direction – Lagaan
		2003 – National Film Award for Best Music Direction – Kannathil Muthamittal
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
<item>
  <id>14</id>
  <type>Cultural</type>
  <name>Ludwig van Beethoven</name>
  <img>beethoven</img>
  <bdate>December 16, 1770, Bonn, Germany</bdate>
  <ddate>March 26, 1827, Vienna, Austria</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Music is a higher revelation than all wisdom and philosophy.</quote>
  <info>Composer Ludwig van Beethoven was baptized on December 17, 1770, in Bonn, Germany. He was an innovator, widening the scope of sonata, symphony, concerto and quartet, and combining vocals and instruments in a new way. His personal life was marked by a struggle against deafness, and some of his most important works were composed during the last 10 years of his life, when he was quite unable to hear.
  
		Ludwig van Beethoven is widely considered the greatest composer of all time. He is the crucial transitional figure connecting the Classical and Romantic ages of Western music. Beethoven's body of musical compositions stands with Shakespeare's plays at the outer limits of human accomplishment.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_4IRMYuE1hI</video>
  <video_id>_4IRMYuE1hI</video_id>
  <achievements>
		Ludwig van Beethoven was one of the great musicians and composers during the transition from the Classical to the Romantic periods in Western music.
		
		He was first recognized as an outstanding instrumentalist, playing both piano and violin in the homes of wealthy patrons and, on the piano, on the concert stage. His repetoire quickly expanded to include his own compositions as well as music featuring his improvisations based on works by others, such as Bach and Mozart.
		
		By 1800, Beethoven was widely known as a composer of great ability. His "melodies, musical development, use of modulation and texture, and characterization of emotion" introduced new methods of presenting and developing musical themes. His musical innovations continued throughout his career, including his expansion of the format of the symphony.
		
		Beethoven set new standards for conveying emotion and passion through his music, created intricate melodies and harmonies that continue to challenge and delight musicians today, and showed himself to be a master of composition for many instruments and musical formats.
  </achievements> 
 </item>
 </menu>


