<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>

<item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Ravi Shankar</name>
  <img>ravishankar</img>
  <bdate>April 7, 1920</bdate>
  <ddate>December 11, 2012</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Pop changes week to week, month to month. But great music is like literature.</quote>
  <info>Ravi Shankar is a legendary sitar player and one of India's most esteemed classical musicians. Pandit Ravi Shankar has made a major contribution in popularizing Indian classical music in the West through his association with The Beatles (especially George Harrison). 

		Pandit Ravi Shankar was born on April 7, 1920 at Varanasi, India. His elder brother Uday Shankar was a famous Indian classical dancer. In his early years Ravi Shankar joined his elder brother, Uday Shankar and his troupe and went to Paris in 1930 to experiment with the stage by playing small roles in ballets for the next three years. 

		In 1938, Ravi Shankar gave up a possible dance career and started learning sitar under Allauddin Khan, founder of the Maihar Gharana of Indian classical music. Ravi Shankar's formal training ended in 1944. Thereafter, Pandit Ravi Shankar joined the IPTA and composed music for several ballets, started Renaissance artistes in 1947 and was in charge of Vadya Vrinda at the All India Radio in 1949. Ravi Shankar first performed outside India in the Soviet Union in 1954. He also performed at major events such as the Edinburgh Festival as well as major venues such as Royal Festival Hall. In 1960s, Ravi Shankar's fusion with George Harrison, a member of The Beatles became very popular in the US and helped in popularizing Indian classical music in the West.

		Pandit Ravi Shankar has won several honours and awards. These include: Padma Vibhushan, Magsaysay Award, two Grammy Awards, Fukuoka Grand Prize from Japan, and the Crystal Award from Davos. In 1999, Ravi Shankar was awarded with Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian honour. He was also a nominated member of the Rajya Sabha, India's upper house of Parliament, from 1986 to 1992.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4gWCiLexilY</video>
  <video_id>4gWCiLexilY</video_id> 
 </item>

<item>
  <id>8</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>William Shakespeare</name>
  <img>shakespeare</img>
  <bdate>April 26, 1564</bdate>
  <ddate>April 23, 1616</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Love all, trust a few, do wrong to none.</quote>
  <info>William Shakespeare was baptized on 26 April 1564. We don't know the exact date of his birth but in the 16th century it was normal for babies to baptized within a few days of their birth (because so many died). Shakespeare was born the same year as Christopher Marlowe.

		William Shakespeare's father John was a glover (maker of gloves) and he seems to have been a leading citizen of Stratford Upon Avon.

		We don't know if John Shakespeare was a native of Stratford but he was living in the town by 1552 because in that year he was fined for leaving a dunghill in Henley Street. At that time Stratford was a small town with a population of between 1,500 and 2,000.
		In 1557 John Shakespeare married a woman from nearby Wilmcote called Mary Arden. The Shakespeares had 8 children. In 1558 the Shakespeare's had a daughter called Joan (she died in 1563). However in 1563 they had another daughter called Margaret but she too died in childhood. After William in 1563 they had a son called Gilbert in 1566. (He died in 1612). They also had another daughter called Joan (like her dead sister) in 1569 and a daughter called Anne in 1571. In 1574 they had a son called Richard (he died in 1613). In 1580 they had a son called Edmund (he died in 1607).

		When he was 18 William Shakespeare married a woman named Anne Hathaway. They married in November 1582 and their daughter Susanna was baptized in May 1583.

		On 2 February 1585 the Shakespeare's next children, a twin boy and girl, Hamnet and Judith were baptized. However Hamnet died when he was 11.

		William Shakespeare probably went to Stratford Grammar School. However we do not know what he did for a living when he was a young man but in about 1587 he went to London. He became an actor and a playwright.

		By 1592 William Shakespeare was making a name for himself. In that year a man named Robert Greene wrote about 'an upstart crow' who 'is in his own conceit the only Shake-scene in a country. He didn't actually name William Shakespeare but it is clear who he meant.

		The theatres in London were closed from 1592 to 1594 because of plague but Shakespeare wrote two poems during that time, Venus and Adonis 1593 and Lucerce in 1594.

		William Shakespeare prospered and in 1597 he bought a house and gardens in Stratford for £60.

		William Shakespeare made his will on 25 March 1616 shortly before he death. He died on 23 April 1616 and was buried in the parish church. Anne Shakespeare died in 1623. Susanna died in 1649 and Judith, the surviving twin died in 1662.

		In the 19th century as Stratford upon Avon became famous as the birthplace of William Shakespeare. The house where he was born was purchased in 1847 and turned into a monument. Anne Hathaway's cottage was purchased in 1892. The Royal Shakespeare Theatre was built in 1932 and the Shakespeare Centre opened in 1964.

		Today William Shakespeare is remembered as one of the greatest English playwrights.
	</info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xc2MQh_GwkQ</video>
  <video_id>xc2MQh_GwkQ</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Ali Akbar Khan</name>
  <img>aliakbarkhan</img>
  <bdate>April 14, 1922</bdate>
  <ddate>June 18, 2009</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Real music is not for wealth, not for honours or even the joys of the mind... but as a path for realisation and salvation.</quote>
  <info>Ustad Ali Akbar Khan was one of the most accomplished Indian classical musicians, admired all over the world for his brilliant compositions and his mastery of the sarode. Ustad Ali Akbar Khan is considered by many as the "Indian Johann Sebastian Bach."

		Ali Akbar Khan was born on April 14, 1922 in East Bengal (Bangladesh). His family traces its gharana (ancestral tradition) to Mian Tansen, a 16th century musical genius and court musician of Emperor Akbar. Khan's father, the late Padma Vibhusan Acharya Dr. Allauddin Khan, was regarded as the greatest figure in North Indian music in 20th century. Khan started learning music at the age of three. He learnt vocal music from his father and drums from his uncle, Fakir Aftabuddin. He learnt how to play several other musical instruments too, but finally decided to concentrate on the sarode and vocal. 

		Khan gave his first public performance in Allahabad, at the age of thirteen. In his early twenties, he made his first recording in Lucknow, for the HMV label. The next year, he became the court musician to the Maharaja of Jodhpur. He worked there for seven years and the state of Jodhpur bestowed upon him the title of Ustad. Several years later (1993), Ustad Ali Akbar Khan received the title of Hathi Saropao and Dowari Tajeem, at Jodhpur Palace's Golden Jubilee Celebration.

		Khan first visited the United States in 1955, on the request of Lord Menuhin and gave a memorable concert at the Museum of Modern Art in New York. He played a major role in popularizing Indian classical music in the US. He also founded the Ali Akbar College of Music in Calcutta, India, in the year 1956. Khan began teaching music in America in 1965. Later, he founded the Ali Akbar College of Music, in Marin County, California.

		Ustad Ali Akbar Khan gave music in several films. These include: "Aandhiyan" by Chetan Anand (1953), "House Holder" by Ivory/Merchant, "Khudita Pashan" (for which he won the "Best Musician of the Year" Award), "Devi" by Satyajit Ray, and "Little Buddha" by Bernardo Bertolucci. In 1997, he was chosen for the Asian Paints Shiromani Award - Hall of Fame. He was the second recipient of the award, after Satyajit Ray.

		Ustad Ali Akbar Khan left for the holy abode on June 19, 2009, in San Francisco (United States Of America), after suffering from a kidney ailment for quite sometime. He was on dialysis and his condition had deteriorated in the last four months preceding his death. He breathed his last at his music centre, at the age of 88. The Sarod maestro is survived by his wife Mary and eleven children, apart from his musical legacy that includes the Ali Akbar College of Music in San Rafael, California.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r17LmpFCAFQ</video> 
  <video_id>r17LmpFCAFQ</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>M. S. Subbulakshmi</name>
  <img>mssubbulakshmi</img>
  <bdate>September 16, 1916</bdate>
  <ddate>December 11, 2004</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>My greatest fear is giving performances. I feel I am responsible for the audience but I am also scared of them.</quote>
  <info>MS Subbulakshmi was a legendary Carnatic musician. She was popularly known as Nightingale of India. Her rendering of bhajans (devotional songs) was divine and used to enthrall and transfix listeners, and transport them into a different world

		MS Subbulakshmi (Madurai Shanmukhavadivu Subbulakshmi) was born as Kunjamma in the temple city of Madurai on September 16, 1916. She was born into a family of musicians. Her grandmother Akkammal played the violin and her mother was a veena artist. 

		MS Subbulakshmi started learning Carnatic music from a very early age. She made her debut as a singer at the age of eight and went on to perform in concerts, a domain traditionally reserved for males. She began her Carnatic classical music training under Semmangudi Srinivasa Iyer and then Hindustani classical training under Pandit Narayan Rao Vyas.

		By the age of 17, Subbulakshmi was giving concerts on her own, including major performances at the Madras Music Academy, the prestigious center for the study and promotion of Carnatic music. In 1940, she married T. Sadasivam, a freedom fighter, and a follower of Rajaji. He played a key role in advancing her career.

		She also acted in a few Tamil films in her youth. Her first movie "Sevasadanam" was released in 1938. MS Subbulakshmi also played the male role of Narada in "Savitri" (1941) to raise money for launching Kalki, her husband's nationalist Tamil weekly. Her title role of the Rajasthani saint-poetess Meera in the eponymous film (1945) gave her national prominence. This movie was re-made in Hindi in 1947. The movie had M.S Subbulakshmi. sing the famous Meera bhajans, with Dilipkumar Roy as the music director. Those renditions by M.S. continue to haunt listeners to this day. Following the success of the film she quit films and turned wholly to concert music.

		MS Subbulakshmi traveled to London, New York, Canada, the Far East, and other places as India's cultural ambassador. Her concerts at Carnegie Hall, New York; the UN General Assembly on UN day in 1966; the Royal Albert Hall, London in 1982; and at the Festival of India in Moscow in 1987 were significant landmarks in her career. 

		MS Subbulakshmi received many honours and awards. These include Padma Bhushan in 1954, Sangeetha Kalanidhi in 1968 (She was the first woman recipient of the title), Ramon Magsaysay award in 1974, the Padma Vibhushan in 1975, the Kalidasa Samman in 1988, the Indira Gandhi Award for National Integration in 1990, and the Bharat Ratna in 1998. She was also honored as the court-singer of Tirumala Tirupati Devasthanams.

		After the death of her husband Sadasivam in 1997, MS Subbulakshmi stopped all her public performances. She had no children. MS Subbulakshmi died on December 11, 2004 after a brief illness.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lGuuavo2JHU</video>
  <video_id>lGuuavo2JHU</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 
 <item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Bhimsen Joshi</name>
  <img>panditbhimsenjoshi</img>
  <bdate>February 4, 1922</bdate>
  <ddate>January 24, 2011</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Had I not been a singer, I would have loved to spend my entire life in a garage fine-tuning a Fiat or a Maruti.</quote>
  <info>One of the most prominent and legendary Hindustani vocalist living today is of course Pandit Bhimsen Joshi. He can very easily be called a living legend and someone who has not just earned true fans but has also won over critics. Born on 4th February, 1922 in Karnataka, Pandit Bhimsen Joshi is the descendant of Kirana stream of Hindustani classical music. He is famous for the "Khayal", a form of Hindustani classical. Bhimsen Joshi was interested in music since a very young age and at the age of 11 he left home in search of a Guru. Read the fascinating life history of Pt. Bhimsen Joshi in this short biography. 

		He found the apt teacher for him very close to his house. Under the tutelage of Savai Gandharva he learnt many ragas and perfected his tone, pitch and the best of Kirana gharana. His sheer determination and hard work has made him what he is today. In the last five decades, his popularity has increased manifold because of the intensity and passion he brings in his songs. Other concert artists truly appreciate his style and the passion that he gets into his songs. His first public performance was at the age of 19. 

		Bhimsen Joshi has perfected not just the Khayal interpretations but has also sung Bhajans in Hindi and Marathi. His bhajans are widely heard by not just ardent music lovers but people all over. This versatile singer has also recorded Kannada Dasa Krithis in Dasavani, which are usually sung by Carnatic musicians. His sheer grit and determination earned him his first Platinum Disc in 1986. He has also been presented the Padma Shree in 1972, the Sangeet Natak Akademi Award in 1976 and the Padma Bhushan in 1985. Perhaps some of his best performances have been at Savai Gandharva Sangeet Mahotsav, which is held in Pune annually. It has been a regular feature since the past 3 decades and has become an institution of sorts. 

		His most memorable performance that is remembered till date is of course the national integration song "Mile Sur Mera Tumhara". His golden voice appealing to Indians to come together and stand as one nation is an evergreen number that is hummed by one and all even today. He has collaborated with many other renowned musicians like Hariprasad Chaurasiya, Pandit Ravi Shankar and Dr. Balamuralikrishna and has come out with many albums. He is a living legend who continues to weave magic with his unique voice even today.
	</info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TMpRu8yYjTA</video>
  <video_id>TMpRu8yYjTA</video_id>  
 </item>
 
 
  <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Lata Mangeshkar</name>
  <img>latamangeshkar</img>
  <bdate>September 28, 1929</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>I have decided that I won't take up assignments that don't interest me.</quote>
  <info>Lata Mangeshkar is one of the best singers of the Hindi film industry. She is listed in the Guinness Book of World Records as the most recorded artist in the world. It is estimated that she has more than 30,000 solo, duet and chorus backed songs in 20 different languages from 1948 to 1987. Now, it must way over 40,000! Lata Mangeshkar was born on 28th September, 1929 in a place called Indore. Her father Dinanath Mangeshkar was a renowned classical singer himself. Lata was introduced to music at a very young age. The life history of Lata Mangeshkar is truly fascinating. Read this short biography of Lata Mungeshkar. 

		Lata Mangeshkar was very young when her father passed away, thus making the family dependant on Lata. To take care of her family's economic situation, Lata acted in as many as 8 films from 1942 to 1948. She debuted as playback singer in a Marathi film named Kiti Hasaal (1942). Unfortunately the song was edited out. Her first Hindi playback was for the film Aap ke Sewa Main (1947) but she did not get noticed. At that time, the film industry was ruled by female singers who had heavier and huskier voices like Noor Jehan, Shamshad Begum and Zohrabai Ambalewali. While auditioning for the movie Shaheed (1948), she was rejected on the account of her thin voice! But Ghulam Haider saw the potential in her and gave her a chance to sing in the film Majboor. 

		The song Dil Mera Toda finally got her noticed and it was touted as her breakthrough song. In 1949, she had four major hits from the films Barsaat, Andaaz, Dulari and Mahal. The song "Aayega Aanewala" from Mahal was a huge hit and Lata secured a firm position in the industry. The husky voices of all other singers became obsolete in front of the high pitched voice of Lata Mangeshkar. The music industry had a huge makeover with the arrival of Lata Mangeshkar. By the late 50's, the younger sister of Lata Mangeshkar known as Asha Bhonsle also came into the scene and they both were touted as the unbeatable voices of the industry. 

		Lata rose to fame rapidly and made her indelible mark in the industry. She has sung with famous singers like Mohammed Rafi, Kishore Kumar, Mukesh, etc. She has perfected almost every genre of music. Her success and determination made her one of the most powerful women in the industry. She refused to sing for the great composer S.D Burman due to some misunderstanding and also stopped singing with Mohammed Rafi. Her power was so immense that they had to come back to her. She actually monopolized the music industry and every music director wanted to work with her. She understood the requirement of each song and sang flawlessly. 

		Lata Mangeshkar has been honored with innumerable awards but the one that truly deserves a special mention is that she is the only second singer in the non-classical category (after M.S Subbulakshmi) in India to have received the highest civilian award, Bharat Ratna. She has received three national awards and eight Filmfare awards after which she stopped accepting awards in order to promote new talent. She continues to sing every now and then for Hindi movies and perform live. Truly a living legend, Lata Mangeshkar has a talent that is second to none.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ou0B9T89L0g</video>
  <video_id>Ou0B9T89L0g</video_id>   
 </item>
 
  <item>
  <id>9</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>William Hung</name>
  <img>williamhung</img>
  <bdate>January 13, 1983</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Whatever you believe in, and if you keep trying, you can eventually succeed.</quote>
  <info>William Hung became famous by performing badly in a televised audition for the talent show American Idol. Hung's tone-deaf performance of the Ricky Martin tune "She Bangs" was greeted with sneers by judge Simon Cowell, but Hung's plucky reply became famous: "I already gave my best, and I have no regrets at all." Video of his comically clumsy dance moves began circulating on the Internet early in 2004 and Hung grew into a public phenomenon. He went along with the gag and began accepting invitations to perform "She Bangs" at Cal events, then on TV talk shows and even in concerts nationwide, often with a backing chorus of dancing girls. It was never quite clear if fans were mocking Hung's lack of talent or saluting his cheerful persistence, and Hung himself has continued to insist that he wants to pursue a career in music. His album Inspiration debuted at #34 on the Billboard album charts upon its release in April of 2004.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9RrLQUN8UJg</video>
  <video_id>9RrLQUN8UJg</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 
 
 <item>
  <id>6</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Zakir Hussain</name>
  <img>zakirhussain</img>
  <bdate>March 9, 1951</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>There's drums, there's rhythm, there's dance, there's song. All these come together in hopefully one balanced and very cohesive performance.</quote>
  <info>Zakir Hussain is a classical tabla virtuoso and the most famous tabla player in India today. His contribution in the field of percussion and in the music world at large is highly appreciated. 

		Ustad Zakir Hussain was born on March 9, 1951. His father Ustad Allarakha was himself an established tabla player. Zakir Hussain did his schooling from St. Michael's High School in Mahim and completed his graduation from St Xaviers, Mumbai. Zakir Hussain was a child prodigy and started touring by the age of twelve. He came to the United States in 1970 and started his international career. 

		Zakir Hussain is widely considered as the chief architect of the contemporary world music movement. He founded much historic collaboration. These include: Shakti, which he founded with John McLaughlin and L. Shankar, the Diga Rhythm Band, Making Music, Planet Drum with Mickey Hart, and recordings and performances with a number of artists such as George Harrison, Joe Henderson, Van Morrison, Jack Bruce, Tito Puente, Pharoah Sanders, Billy Cobham, the Hong Kong Symphony and the New Orleans Symphony. 

		In 1987, Zakir Hussain's first solo release, "Making Music," was acclaimed as "one of the most inspired East-West fusion albums ever recorded." In 1988, Zakir Hussain became the youngest percussionist to ever be awarded the title of "Padma Shri" by the Indian government. In 1990, he was awarded the Indo-American Award in recognition for his outstanding cultural contribution to relations between the United States and India. In April, 1991, Zakir Hussain was presented with the Sangeet Natak Akademi Award by the President of India. Zakir Hussain is also the recipient of the 1999 National Heritage Fellowship, the United States' most prestigious honor for a master in the traditional arts.

		Zakir Hussain has composed soundtracks for several movies, notable among them are "In Custody" and "The Mystic Masseur" by Ismail Merchant. Zakir Hussain has also played tabla on the soundtracks of Francis Coppola's "Apocalypse Now", Bernardo Bertolucci's "Little Buddha".

  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=As1OMMcHXFs</video>
  <video_id>As1OMMcHXFs</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>11</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Michael Jackson</name>
  <img>michaeljackson</img>
  <bdate>August 29, 1958</bdate>
  <ddate>June 25, 2009</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Let us dream of tomorrow where we can truly love from the soul, and know love as the ultimate truth at the heart of all creation.</quote>
  <info>Michael Jackson was unquestionably the biggest pop star of the '80s, and certainly one of the most popular recording artists of all time. In his prime, Jackson was an unstoppable juggernaut, possessed of all the tools to dominate the charts seemingly at will: an instantly identifiable voice, eye-popping dance moves, stunning musical versatility, and loads of sheer star power. His 1982 blockbuster Thriller became the biggest-selling album of all time (probably his best-known accomplishment), and he was the first black artist to find stardom on MTV, breaking down innumerable boundaries both for his race and for music video as an art form. Yet as Jackson's career began, very gradually, to descend from the dizzying heights of his peak years, most of the media's attention focused on his increasingly bizarre eccentricities; he was often depicted as a man-child in a state of arrested development, completely sheltered from adult reality by a life spent in show business. The snickering turned to scandal in 1993, when Jackson was accused of molesting a 13-year-old boy; although he categorically denied the charges, his out-of-court settlement failed to restore his tarnished image. He never quite escaped the stigma of those allegations, and while he continued to sell records at superstar-like levels, he didn't release them with enough frequency (or, many critics thought, inspiration) to once again become better known for his music than his private life. Whether as a pop icon or a tabloid caricature, Jackson always remained bigger than life.
  
	   In the wake of his death, everyone in the world seemed to talk of his or her favorite Jackson song, or favorite Jackson dance move or favorite Jackson video. I'll never forget that night back in early 1983, when onstage in Pasadena, California, at the Motown 25th anniversary show, Michael Jackson gave his first public performance as a mature artist staking his own claim, vaulting into that astonishingly graceful, electrifying version of "Billie Jean." Dancing, spinning, sending out impassioned, fierce glares at the overcome audience, Jackson did a powerful job of animating and mythologizing his own blend of mystery and sexuality. I'd never seen anything quite like it before. Maybe I never will again. Michael Jackson didn't just grab the gold ring: He hooked it to a new bar and set it even higher, and nobody has yet snatched it with quite the same flair or results.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_4IRMYuE1hI</video>
  <video_id>_4IRMYuE1hI</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 
 <item>
  <id>7</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>A. R. Rahman</name>
  <img>rahman</img>
  <bdate>January 6, 1967</bdate>
  <ddate></ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Your inner voice is the voice of divinity. To hear it, we need to be in solitude, even in crowded places.</quote>
  <info>Allah Rakha Rahman, who is better known as AR Rahman, is a world-class musician of India. Born as A. S. Dileep Kumar on 6 January 1967 at Chennai in Tamil Nadu, AR Rahman holds the credit for totally overhauling the style in which music was being made in India. Soundtracks and scores composed by him for Indian films have a strong impression of classical, folk, jazz, reggae, soft rock and other genres. Due to his creative brilliance, AR Rahman is often referred to as the Mozart of Madras by his fans in India and abroad. 

		The biography of AR Rahman's career spans somewhere over a decade, but he has already sold over one hundred million records world-wide and more than two hundred million cassettes. This has brought Rahman into the category of the world's top 25 all-time top selling recording artists. Though AR Rahman is the undisputed leader in Indian contemporary music in the present times, he has seen his share of struggle in the professional life.
	
		His father, R K Shekhar, who was a composer, arranger and conductor for Malayalam films died when Rahman was just 9 years-old and his family rented out musical equipment as a source of income. Later there was a turning point when Dileep Kumar decided to rechristen himself as A R Rahman. This incident happened when Rahman's sister was very ill once. A Muslim friend suggested if he prayed in a particular mosque, his sister would recover and so did happen. This caused the entire family to convert to Islam. 

		The life history of AR Rahman's music career started scaling upwards 1991 onwards when began his own studio and started making music for advertisements, television channels and so on. Rahman got his very first break into the Indian film industry when film director, Mani Ratnam offered him a chance to compose music for his Tamil film, Roja at mere Rs 25,000. This movie turned out to be blockbuster hit and then there was no looking back for A.R. Rahman. 

		Roja debut made AR Rahman bag the Rajat Kamal award for best music director at the National Film Awards. This was a historic moment as for the first time ever in Indian film industry, this award was being handed to a first-time film composer. There was no looking back for AR Rahman after this as film offers just started pouring in. There are now an impressive number of music tracks created by Rahman and all of them have sold like hot cakes across India and even abroad. He has made songs for super hit films like Rangeela, Dil Se Taal, Rang De Basanti, Bombay et al.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Sp6wUe9gMrw</video>
  <video_id>Sp6wUe9gMrw</video_id> 
 </item>
 
 
   <item>
  <id>10</id>
  <type>Entertainment</type>
  <name>Ludwig van Beethoven</name>
  <img>beethoven</img>
  <bdate>December 16, 1770</bdate>
  <ddate>March 26, 1827</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Music is a higher revelation than all wisdom and philosophy.</quote>
  <info>Composer Ludwig van Beethoven was baptized on December 17, 1770, in Bonn, Germany. He was an innovator, widening the scope of sonata, symphony, concerto and quartet, and combining vocals and instruments in a new way. His personal life was marked by a struggle against deafness, and some of his most important works were composed during the last 10 years of his life, when he was quite unable to hear.
  
		Ludwig van Beethoven is widely considered the greatest composer of all time. He is the crucial transitional figure connecting the Classical and Romantic ages of Western music. Beethoven's body of musical compositions stands with Shakespeare's plays at the outer limits of human accomplishment.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_4IRMYuE1hI</video>
  <video_id>_4IRMYuE1hI</video_id> 
 </item>
 </menu>


