<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>

<item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>A.P.J. Abdul Kalam</name>
  <img>abdulkalam</img>
  <audio>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qhqtTvLQtVA</audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=59gCGLDz7ww</video>
  <bdate>October 15, 1931</bdate>
  <quote>Man needs his difficulties because they are necessary to enjoy success.</quote>
  <info>Little did Jainulabdeen and Ashiamma know that their son would grow up to be the first citizen of India. An Indian scientist and administrator, Kalam served as the 11th President of India from 2002 until 2007. One amongst the most respected people of the country, Kalam has contributed immensely both as a scientist and as a president. His contribution at the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has been immense. He was responsible for numerous projects such as Project Devil and Project Valiant and launch of the Rohini-1, besides developing missiles under the missions Agni and Prithvi. For the same, he has been popularly tagged as the "Missile Man of India". Kalam has been honored with great laurels and awards for his work by both the Government of India and other countries. Currently, Kalam serves as a visiting professor in various esteemed institutes and universities of India.</info>
 </item>


<item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>Albert Einstein</name>
  <img>alberteinstein</img>
  <bdate>March 14, 1879</bdate>
  <ddate>April 18, 1955</ddate>
  <audio>http://www.einstein-website.de/z_biography/einstein1930.mp3,    http://www.aip.org/history/einstein/sound/voice1.mp3</audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-1Z2wi2uSA</video>
  <quote>The important thing is not to stop questioning. Curiosity has its own reason for existing.</quote>
  <info>Do you fondly call the whiz kid in your class/ organization 'Einstein'? If yes, then you aren't the only one who does so. People around the world honor their friends and acquaintance with the title of 'Einstein' for the person's immaculate brilliance and genius mind. While there may be a lot of genius mind set at work to this date, only once in a century is Albert Einstein born. The 19th century not just witnessed the birth of Albert Einstein, but with it, the birth of modern physics. Rightly known as the Father of Modern Physics, Albert Einstein was, without a doubt, the most influential physicist of the 20th century. With his research and finding, Einstein created a revolution in the field of science. Amongst his numerous works: (a) the general theory of relativity, which provided a unified description of gravity as a geometric property of space and time, and (b) photoelectric effect that established the quantum theory within physics are the most important ones. During his lifetime, Einstein published more than 300 scientific papers, apart from 150 non-scientific works. He was the proud recipient of numerous awards, such as Nobel Prize in Physics, Copley Medal, Matteucci Medal and Max Planck medal. Other than these, he has also been credited by the Times magazine as the Person of the Century. Such was his contribution to mankind that his name Einstein has been made synonymous to being "genius".</info>
 </item>  
 
 <item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>Alfred Nobel</name>
  <img>alfrednobel</img>
  <audio>       </audio>
  <bdate>October 21, 1833</bdate>
  <ddate>December 10, 1896</ddate>
  <discoveries>Dynamite</discoveries>
  <quote>If I have a thousand ideas and only one turns out to be good, I am satisfied.</quote>
  <info>Alfred Bernhard Nobel was a Swedish inventor, engineer and industrialist who had obtained a total of 355 patents in his lifetime. He was most well-known for inventing dynamite, and for developing some more powerful explosives and detonators to effectively ignite them. He built a network of almost a hundred factories all over the world to manufacture explosives and ammunition, and amassed a massive fortune from his businesses. In fact, at the time of his death, he was one of the wealthiest persons on the world. Since he was unmarried and childless, there were many speculations about the contents of his last will which he had signed on 27th November, 1895. The contents of his will caused a lot of disappointment to his much hopeful extended family as Nobel had left much of his wealth for the establishment of an international prize fund! As the inventor of dynamite, he had earned the sobriquet, 'The Merchant of Death' which deeply traumatized Nobel who was a pacifist at heart. He did not want to be remembered as the reason behind mass destruction after his death, and in order to redeem his posthumous reputation, he left the major portion of his wealth for the establishment of the Nobel Prizes to be awarded for eminence in five different fields, without any discrimination on basis of nationality.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC-sN5lbfhE</video>
 </item> 
 
 
 <item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>C. V. Raman</name>
  <img>cvraman</img>
  <audio>       </audio>
  <bdate>November 7th, 1888</bdate>
  <ddate>November 21, 1970</ddate>
  <discoveries>He was the first Indian scholar who studied wholly in India received the Nobel Prize.Raman effect</discoveries>
  <quote>The true wealth of a nation consists not in the stored- up gold but in the intellectual and physical strength of its people.</quote>
  <info>Chandrasekhara Venkata Raman was born at Tiruchirappalli in Southern India on November 7th, 1888. His father was a lecturer in mathematics and physics so that from the first he was immersed in an academic atmosphere. He entered Presidency College, Madras, in 1902, and in 1904 passed his B.A. examination, winning the first place and the gold medal in physics; in 1907 he gained his M.A. degree, obtaining the highest distinctions.
		
		His earliest researches in optics and acoustics - the two fields of investigation to which he has dedicated his entire career - were carried out while he was a student.
		
		Since at that time a scientific career did not appear to present the best possibilities, Raman joined the Indian Finance Department in 1907; though the duties of his office took most of his time, Raman found opportunities for carrying on experimental research in the laboratory of the Indian Association for the Cultivation of Science at Calcutta (of which he became Honorary Secretary in 1919).
		
		In 1917 he was offered the newly endowed Palit Chair of Physics at Calcutta University, and decided to accept it. After 15 years at Calcutta he became Professor at the Indian Institute of Science at Bangalore (1933-1948), and since 1948 he is Director of the Raman Institute of Research at Bangalore, established and endowed by himself. He also founded the Indian Journal of Physics in 1926, of which he is the Editor. Raman sponsored the establishment of the Indian Academy of Sciences and has served as President since its inception. He also initiated the Proceedings of that academy, in which much of his work has been published, and is President of the Current Science Association, Bangalore, which publishes Current Science (India).
		
		Some of Raman's early memoirs appeared as Bulletins of the Indian Associationfor the Cultivation of Science (Bull. 6 and 11, dealing with the "Maintenance of Vibrations"; Bull. 15, 1918, dealing with the theory of the musical instruments of the violin family). He contributed an article on the theory of musical instruments to the 8th Volume of the Handbuch der Physik, 1928. In 1922 he published his work on the "Molecular Diffraction of Light", the first of a series of investigations with his collaborators which ultimately led to his discovery, on the 28th of February, 1928, of the radiation effect which bears his name ("A new radiation", Indian J. Phys., 2 (1928) 387), and which gained him the 1930 Nobel Prize in Physics.
		
		Other investigations carried out by Raman were: his experimental and theoretical studies on the diffraction of light by acoustic waves of ultrasonic and hypersonic frequencies (published 1934-1942), and those on the effects produced by X-rays on infrared vibrations in crystals exposed to ordinary light. In 1948 Raman, through studying the spectroscopic behaviour of crystals, approached in a new manner fundamental problems of crystal dynamics. His laboratory has been dealing with the structure and properties of diamond, the structure and optical behaviour of numerous iridescent substances (labradorite, pearly felspar, agate, opal, and pearls).
		
		Among his other interests have been the optics of colloids, electrical and magnetic anisotropy, and the physiology of human vision.
		
		Raman has been honoured with a large number of honorary doctorates and memberships of scientific societies. He was elected a Fellow of the Royal Society early in his career (1924), and was knighted in 1929.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L0IlhgZjQp0</video>
 </item> 
 
  <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>Srinivasa Ramanujan</name>
  <img>srinivasaramanujan</img>
  <audio>       </audio>
  <bdate>December 22, 1887</bdate>
  <ddate>April 26, 1920</ddate>
  <discoveries>Mathematics</discoveries>
  <quote>An equation means nothing to me unless it expresses a thought of God.</quote>
  <info>Ramanujan belonged to a Brahman family, but his father was poor and served as a bookkeeper in the firm of a cloth merchant in Kumbakonam. At the age of seven, after two years in elementary school, he transferred to the high school at Kumbakonam. In 1897 he placed first in the Tanjore primary examination. Ramanujan early studied some trigonometry on his own; real enthusiasm for the subject arose in 1903, when he was able to borrow an English text, Carr’s Synopsis of Pure Mathematics. From then on, mathematics was nearly his only interest. He jotted down his results in a notebook which he carried with him and showed to people who were interested.

		Quiet and meditative, Ramanujan was very fond of numerical calculations and had an unusual memory for numbers. In 1904 he won a fellowship at Government College, Kumbakonam. His excessive devotion to mathematics and neglect of English, a fundamental subject, led to his failure to be promoted. He returned to the college after traveling but could not graduate. He briefly attended a college in Madras, then returned to Kumbakonam, where he again failed. For several years he had no definite occupation but continued to record his mathematical results.

		In 1909 Ramanujan married and was compelled to earn a living. He went to Ramaswami Aiyar, the founder of the Indian Mathematical Society, then deputy collector in the little town of Tirukkoyilur, to ask for a minor clerical job. He was sent on to Seshu Aayar, one of Ramanujan’s former teachers, and obtained a substitute office job for a few months. He was then recommended to Ramachaudra Rao, collector of Nellore, eighty miles north of Madras, who was interested in mathematics; he later described Ramanujan at the time of the interview:

		A short uncouth figure, stout, unshaved, not over-clean, with one conspicuous feature—shining eyes-walked in with a frayed notebook under his arm. He was miserably poor.—He opened his book and began to explain some of his discoveries. I saw quite at once that there was something out of the way; but my knowledge did not permit me to judge whether he talked sense or nonsense. Suspending judgment, I asked him to come over again, and he did. And then he had gauged my ignorance and shewed me some of his simpler results. These transcended existing books, and I had no doubt he was a remarkable man. Then, step by step, he led me to elliptic integrals and hypergeometric series and at last his theory of divergent series not yet announced to the world converted me. I asked him what he wanted. He said he wanted a pittance to live on so that he might pursue his researches.

		Rao was convinced that a job as a clerk was not the answer to Ramanujan’s troubles and sent him back to Madras, where Rao supported him for a while and tried unsuccessfully to get a fellowship for him. When this did not succeed, Ramanujan in 1912 found a job in the office of the Madras Port Trust. At this time he began his mathematical publication in the Journal of the Indian Mathematical Society. His first paper, “Some Properties of Bernoulli’s Numbers,” was followed by a number of brief communications on series and infinite products and a geometric approximate construction of p.

		Encouraged by influential friends interested in his mathematical work, Ramanujan began a correspondence with G. H. Hardy of Cambridge, one of the world’s foremost specialists in analytic number theory. In his first letter Ramanujan mentioned his investigations on the distribution of primes and then added more than 100 theorems he had found in various parts of mathematics. Hardy was duly impressed and invited Ramanujan to come to England but, being a Brahman, he had scruples about leaving India. Instead a two-year fellowship was arranged for him at the University of Madras.

		Hardy was disappointed and continued to attempt to persuade Ramanujan to come to Cambridge. When his colleague E. H. Neville lectured in Madras, he approached the young man and this time obtained his consent. Very favorable fellowship arrangements were made, and Ramanujan was admitted to Trinity College in 1914. He developed rapidly under the guidance of Hardy and Littlewood, who also helped him to publish his papers in English periodicals. Aside from the dozen papers in the Journal of the Indian Mathematical Society, questions proposed, and notes from the proceedings of meetings, Ramanujan published twenty-onepapers during his five-year stay in Europe, several of them in collaboration with Hardy.

		It was inevitable that a large portion of Ramanujan’s results from his notebooks consisted of rediscoveries; he had never had systematic training in mathematics or access to a good library. To quote Hardy: “What was to be done in the way of teaching him modern mathematics? The limitations of his knowledge were as startling as its profundity.” He worked with modular equations and theorems of complex multiplication, yet had no notion of doubly periodic functions; he worked with analytic number theory and had only the vaguest idea of what a function of a complex variable was. Most of the theorems in the notebooks were not proved in the standard sense but were only made plausible: “His ideas as to what constituted a mathematical proof were of the most shadowy description. All his results, new or old, right or wrong, had been arrived at by a process of mingled argument, intuition and induction, of which he was entirely unable to give any coherent account.” Ramanujan’s investigations on the distribution of primes suffered particularly from these weaknesses and therefore contributed little to the development of the general theory.

		Ramanujan’s first paper published in Europe, “Modular Equations and Approximations to p” contained a number of peculiar and very good approximations to p, many of them by means of square root expressions. Of greater systematic interest is his long memoir “Highly Composite Numbers,” in which he derived some important properties of these numbers. Ramanujan returned to the question of the average number of prime divisors of a number in a paper written with Hardy,’The Normal Number of Prime Factors of a Number n.”

		The part of Ramanujan’s work that stimulated most contributions from later mathematicians is probably his study of the partition of numbers into summands. From MacMahon’s extensive numerical calculations of the number p(n) of partitions of a number n, Ramanujan conjectured that these integers must have simple congruence properties with respect to small primes and their powers. He was able to prove some of these results by means of formulas from the theory of elliptic functions; others have been derived later. These papers by Ramanujan on partitions were followed by a joint paper with Hardy on the asymptotic value of p(n). Their result was remarkable, since not only did their formula give good approximations to the values already calculated but also seemed to give an exact expression for p(n); Rademacher later established that this was correct.

		Ramanujan’s other work comprised a variety of topics, mainly of a combinatorial nature. He wrote on the representation of integers as the sum of squares and on the lattice points inside a circle; in function theory he produced several papers on definite integrals, as well as on elliptic, hypergeometric, and modular functions.

		In 1917 Ramanujan fell ill, possibly with tuberculosis; and the remainder of his stay in England was spent in several sanatoriums. In 1918 he was elected a fellow of the Royal Society and in the same year a fellow of Trinity College. These high distinctions seemed to improve his health and stimulate his mathematical production. Nevertheless, since the English climate did not seem to be beneficial, it was decided to send him back to India. An annual allowance of £250 for five years was awarded him by the University of Madras, with prospects of a later professorship.

		Ramanujan returned to Madras in April 1919 in a precarious state of health. A difficult patient who refused medical aid, he went for a while to his home district but was prevailed upon to return to Madras for treatment. Until his last days he continued his mathematical research.
  </info>
  <video></video>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>6</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>Thomas Alva Edison</name>
  <img>thomasedison</img>
  <bdate>February 11, 1847</bdate>
  <ddate>October 18, 1931</ddate>
  <audio>https://ia600307.us.archive.org/29/items/ThomasAlvaEdison-speaking/ThomasA.Edison-LetUsNotForget1919.mp3</audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bc4qfMNSQ34</video>
  <quote>Genius is one percent inspiration, ninety-nine percent perspiration.</quote>
  <info>Thomas Alva Edison was the most prolific inventor in American history. He amassed a record 1,093 patents covering key innovations and minor improvements in wide range of fields, including telecommunications, electric power, sound recording, motion pictures, primary and storage batteries, and mining and cement technology. As important, he broadened the notion of invention to encompass what we now call innovation-invention, research, development, and commercialization-and invented the industrial research laboratory. Edison's role as an innovator is evident not only in his two major laboratories at Menlo Park and West Orange in New Jersey but in more than 300 companies formed worldwide to manufacture and market his inventions, many of which carried the Edison name, including some 200 Edison illuminating companies.
  </info>
 </item>  
 
 <item>
  <id>7</id>
  <type>ST</type>
  <name>Yellapragada Subbarow</name>
  <img>subbarao</img>
  <bdate>January 12, 1895</bdate>
  <ddate>August 9, 1948</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3odh3Iucyko</video>
  <quote>You've probably never heard of Dr. Yellapragada SubbaRow,Yet because he lived you may live longe</quote>
  <info>Yellapragada Subbarao was born in a poor Telugu 6000 Niyogi Brahmin family in Bhimavaram district in Old Madras Presidency, now in West Godavari district, Andhra Pradesh. He was born as the fourth child amongst seven children to Y. Jagganatham and Y. Venkamma. Though his father worked as a revenue inspector, the family suffered from many hardships of poverty due to the loss of several of his close relatives at a young age. As such, his schooling at Rajahmundry went through a traumatic phase, leading to his completion of matriculation in the third attempt from Hindu High School in Madras. He attained his intermediate education from Presidency College and took admission in Madras Medical College, his education being financed by his friends and Kasturi Suryanarayana Murthy. He later went on to marry Murthy's daughter.
  
		With so many discoveries and developments to his credit, Subbarao never marketed his work and hence, was always left behind in terms of work recognition and appreciation. He always sat in the audience and had to be pushed to the stage by a colleague or a collaborator to take a bow as each of his researches was revealed to the public. Further, he was seen giving interviews to the press or visiting nations on lecture tours. When his colleague George Hitchings won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, along with Gertrude Elion, in 1988, he stated that some of the works initiated by Subbarao had to be rediscovered for the simple reason that his partner Fiske did not allow his contributions earn name and fame, probably out of jealousy. American Cyanamid honored Subbarao by naming a new fungus under his name "Subbaromyces splendens".
  </info>
 </item> 
</menu>


