<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>

<item>
  <id>0</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Aristotle</name>
  <img>aristotle</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=csIW4W_DYX4</video>
  <bdate>384 BC, Chalkidiki, Greece</bdate>
  <ddate>322 BC, Chalcis, Greece</ddate>
  <quote>Love is composed of a single soul inhabiting two bodies.</quote>
<!--   <info>Little did Jainulabdeen and Ashiamma know that their son would grow up to be the first citizen of India. An Indian scientist and administrator, Kalam served as the 11th President of India from 2002 until 2007. One amongst the most respected people of the country, Kalam has contributed immensely both as a scientist and as a president. His contribution at the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has been immense. He was responsible for numerous projects such as Project Devil and Project Valiant and launch of the Rohini-1, besides developing missiles under the missions Agni and Prithvi. For the same, he has been popularly tagged as the "Missile Man of India". Kalam has been honored with great laurels and awards for his work by both the Government of India and other countries. Currently, Kalam serves as a visiting professor in various esteemed institutes and universities of India.</info> -->
 <info>
		Aristotle was a Greek philosopher and scientist born in the Macedonian city of Stagirus, in 384 BCE. His father, Nicomachus, died when Aristotle was a child, whereafter Proxenus of Atarneus became his guardian.At eighteen, he joined Plato's Academy in Athens and remained there until the age of thirty-seven (c. 347 BCE). His writings cover many subjects – including physics, biology, zoology, metaphysics, logic, ethics, aesthetics, poetry, theater, music, rhetoric, linguistics, politics and government – and constitute the first comprehensive system of Western philosophy. Shortly after Plato died, Aristotle left Athens and, at the request of Philip of Macedon, tutored Alexander the Great between 356 and 323 BCE. According to the Encyclopædia Britannica, "Aristotle was the first genuine scientist in history ... [and] every scientist is in his debt."

		Teaching Alexander the Great gave Aristotle many opportunities and an abundance of supplies. He established a library in the Lyceum which aided in the production of many of his hundreds of books. The fact that Aristotle was a pupil of Plato contributed to his former views of Platonism, but, following Plato's death, Aristotle immersed himself in empirical studies and shifted from Platonism to empiricism. He believed all peoples' concepts and all of their knowledge was ultimately based on perception. Aristotle's views on natural sciences represent the groundwork underlying many of his works.

		Aristotle's views on physical science profoundly shaped medieval scholarship. Their influence extended into the Renaissance and were not replaced systematically until the Enlightenment and theories such as classical mechanics. Some of Aristotle's zoological observations were not confirmed or refuted until the 19th century.[examples needed] His works contain the earliest known formal study of logic, which was incorporated in the late 19th century into modern formal logic.

		In metaphysics, Aristotelianism profoundly influenced Judeo-Islamic philosophical and theological thought during the Middle Ages and continues to influence Christian theology, especially the scholastic tradition of the Catholic Church. Aristotle was well known among medieval Muslim intellectuals and revered as "The First Teacher".

		His ethics, though always influential, gained renewed interest with the modern advent of virtue ethics. All aspects of Aristotle's philosophy continue to be the object of active academic study today. Though Aristotle wrote many elegant treatises and dialogues – Cicero described his literary style as "a river of gold" – it is thought that only around a third of his original output has survived.


 </info>
 <achievements>
		Aristotle is famous for his introduction of scientific method and also known for providing important term of science called ‘empiricism’. Like his teacher, his philosophy quite lies in universal approach. He said that universal truths can be known from some particular things through induction. Even when induction was sufficient enough to discover universals by generalizations, it wasn’t succeeding in identifying causes. For this cause, Aristotle had to use deductive reasoning in the form of syllogisms. He developed a complete normative approach to scientific enquiry with the help of syllogism. But there was a difficulty with this scheme; it had problems in showing that derived truths have solid primary premises. Perhaps he could have showed that demonstrations were circular in which conclusions have supported premises and premises must have supported conclusions. But he didn’t allow that.
 
		He didn’t allow the inclusion of infinite number of middle terms between the primary premises and the conclusion. Induction was the only method suitable for this purpose. Aristotle’s writings were more qualitative than quantitative. The main reason of his failings was the lack of concepts like mass, temperature, velocity and force in his research. His writings were considered as a mixture of curious errors and precocious accuracy. For example, his theory of heavier objects fall faster than lighter ones was proved incorrect by the simple experiments of Galileo and John Philoponus. He was also criticized for his simple observation and over-stretched reason in deriving the “laws of universe”. In today’s scientific method, his observations without sufficient facts are considered ineffective. His theory of geocentric cosmology also was proved wrong in terms of modern metaphysics.  

		Aristotle’s approach towards science was different from that of his teacher, Plato. While the latter dedicated his wholly and solely to ‘first philosophy’, that of metaphysics and mathematics, Aristotle believed that it was also very important to study ‘second philosophy’: the world around us, from physics and mechanics to biology. It can be said that Aristotle single handedly invented science as it is today, including various fields and categories. Also, unlike Plato who was only involved with abstract form, Aristotle chose to study minutely the natural world, plants and animals, how they worked, what were they made up of and to understand how each of them fitted in the larger picture of nature. His research and study of nature was idolized on four important causes – matter, form, moving cause and final cause. He wrote in detail about five hundred different animals in his works, including a hundred and twenty kinds of fish and sixty kinds of insect. He was the first to use dissection extensively.
 </achievements>
 </item>

<item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Sir Isaac Newton</name>
  <img>newton</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cn_L1BvUGvg</video>
  <bdate>January 4, 1643, Woolsthorpe-by-Colsterworth, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>March 31, 1727, Kensington, London, United Kingdom</ddate>
  <quote>To every action there is always opposed an equal reaction.</quote>
<!--   <info>Little did Jainulabdeen and Ashiamma know that their son would grow up to be the first citizen of India. An Indian scientist and administrator, Kalam served as the 11th President of India from 2002 until 2007. One amongst the most respected people of the country, Kalam has contributed immensely both as a scientist and as a president. His contribution at the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has been immense. He was responsible for numerous projects such as Project Devil and Project Valiant and launch of the Rohini-1, besides developing missiles under the missions Agni and Prithvi. For the same, he has been popularly tagged as the "Missile Man of India". Kalam has been honored with great laurels and awards for his work by both the Government of India and other countries. Currently, Kalam serves as a visiting professor in various esteemed institutes and universities of India.</info> -->
 <info>
		Sir Isaac Newton was born on Christmas Day, in 1643, to a relatively poor farming family. His father died 3 months before he was born. His mother later remarried, but her second husband did not get on with Isaac; leading to friction between Isaac and his parents. The young Isaac attended school at King’s School, Grantham in Lincolnshire (where his signature is still inscribed in the walls.. Isaac was one of the top students, but before completing his studies his mother withdrew him from school, so Isaac could work as a farmer. It was only through the intervention of the headmaster that Isaac was able to return to finish his studies; he passed his final exams with very good results, and was able to go to Trinity College, Cambridge.

		Newton at Cambridge
		Isaac Newton At Cambridge he was able to pursue his interests in mathematics, science and physics. At the time the prevailing education was based on Aristotle, but Isaac was more interested in modern mathematicians such as Descartes. Isaac Newton had a prodigious capacity to consider mathematical problems, and then focus on them until he had solved the mystery behind them. His one pointed nature led him to, at times, be detached from the world. For example, he had little time for women. An early teenage romance came to nothing, and he remained single throughout his life.

		Sir Isaac Newton, has been referred to as one of the greatest genius’ of history. His mathematical and scientific achievements give credence to such a view. Amongst his many accomplishments in the field of science include:

		Developing a theory of Calculus.
		Unfortunately, at the same time as Newton, calculus was being developed by Leibinz.  When Leibinz published his results, there was a bitter feud between the two men, with Newton claiming plagiarism. This bitter feud lasted until Leibinz death in 1713, it also extended between British mathematicians and the continent.

 </info>
 <achievements>
		Mathematical Achievements of Newton
		
		Generalized binomial theorem
		Newton’s identities,
		Newton’s method,
		classified cubic plane curves (polynomials of degree three in two variables),
		Substantial contributions to the theory of finite differences,
		Use of fractional indices
		Used geometry to derive solutions to Diophantine equations.
		Used power series with confidence and to revert power series.
		Discovered a new formula for pi.
		
		Scientific Achievements of Newton

		Optics – Newton made great advancements into the study of optics. In particular he developed the spectrum by splitting white light through a prism.
		Telescope – Made significant improvements to the development of the telescope. However, when his ideas were criticised by Hooke, Newton withdrew from the public debate. He developed an antagonistic and hostile attitude to Hooke, throughout his life.
		Mechanics and Gravitation. In his famous book Principa Mathematica. Newton explained the three laws of motion that laid the framework for modern physics.
		This involved explaining planetary movements.
</achievements>
</item>

<item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Charles Darwin</name>
  <img>darwin</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XKnqj3YFXU8</video>
  <bdate>February 12, 1809, The Mount, Shrewsbury, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>April 19, 1882, Down House, Downe, United Kingdom</ddate>
  <quote>A man's friendships are one of the best measures of his worth.</quote>
<!--   <info>Little did Jainulabdeen and Ashiamma know that their son would grow up to be the first citizen of India. An Indian scientist and administrator, Kalam served as the 11th President of India from 2002 until 2007. One amongst the most respected people of the country, Kalam has contributed immensely both as a scientist and as a president. His contribution at the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has been immense. He was responsible for numerous projects such as Project Devil and Project Valiant and launch of the Rohini-1, besides developing missiles under the missions Agni and Prithvi. For the same, he has been popularly tagged as the "Missile Man of India". Kalam has been honored with great laurels and awards for his work by both the Government of India and other countries. Currently, Kalam serves as a visiting professor in various esteemed institutes and universities of India.</info> -->
 <info>
		Charles Robert Darwin, was an English naturalist and geologist, best known for his contributions to evolutionary theory. He established that all species of life have descended over time from common ancestors, and in a joint publication with Alfred Russel Wallace introduced his scientific theory that this branching pattern of evolution resulted from a process that he called natural selection, in which the struggle for existence has a similar effect to the artificial selection involved in selective breeding.

		Darwin published his theory of evolution with compelling evidence in his 1859 book On the Origin of Species, overcoming scientific rejection of earlier concepts of transmutation of species. By the 1870s the scientific community and much of the general public had accepted evolution as a fact. However, many favoured competing explanations and it was not until the emergence of the modern evolutionary synthesis from the 1930s to the 1950s that a broad consensus developed in which natural selection was the basic mechanism of evolution. In modified form, Darwin's scientific discovery is the unifying theory of the life sciences, explaining the diversity of life.

		Darwin's early interest in nature led him to neglect his medical education at the University of Edinburgh; instead, he helped to investigate marine invertebrates. Studies at the University of Cambridge (Christ's College) encouraged his passion for natural science. His five-year voyage on HMS Beagle established him as an eminent geologist whose observations and theories supported Charles Lyell's uniformitarian ideas, and publication of his journal of the voyage made him famous as a popular author.

		Puzzled by the geographical distribution of wildlife and fossils he collected on the voyage, Darwin began detailed investigations and in 1838 conceived his theory of natural selection. Although he discussed his ideas with several naturalists, he needed time for extensive research and his geological work had priority. He was writing up his theory in 1858 when Alfred Russel Wallace sent him an essay which described the same idea, prompting immediate joint publication of both of their theories. Darwin's work established evolutionary descent with modification as the dominant scientific explanation of diversification in nature. In 1871 he examined human evolution and sexual selection in The Descent of Man, and Selection in Relation to Sex, followed by The Expression of the Emotions in Man and Animals. His research on plants was published in a series of books, and in his final book, he examined earthworms and their effect on soil.

		Darwin became internationally famous, and his pre-eminence as a scientist was honoured by burial in Westminster Abbey.Darwin has been described as one of the most influential figures in human history.

</info>
 <achievements>
		Darwin got his big break in 1831. A naturalist was needed to travel along on a scientific expedition – a voyage around the world in the brigantine HMBS Beagle under the supervision of Captain Fits Roy. Luckily, some of his Cambridge fellows also recommended him for the place. The voyage took around five years.

		Throughout this voyage, Darwin collected bones of extinct animals. He was curious about the relationship between the extinct animals and the existing ones. The unusual marine iguana, the tortoises and the finches on the Galapagos Islands in the pacific made him perplexed, since similar, yet rather distinct, forms of the same animals were found on separate islands. These observations led to his legendary ideas on evolution.

		After the return, Darwin moved to London for a while and compiled an account of his travels. Darwin got married to his cousin Emma Wedgowood in 1839. The coupled moved to Downe House in Kent in 1844. There, Darwin got a letter from the naturalist Alfred Russel Wallace, who had made similar observations about evolution separately. A collaborative report by Darwin and Wallace was published in 1858. Darwin publicized the theory of evolution in his famous book, “The Origin of Species by Natural Selection”, in 1859. The book, which asserted that all the varied forms of life on earth could, in the course of time, have evolved from a common ancestry, was a huge success. Darwin also commented that in the struggle for life, only the ‘fittest’ creatures would survive while others fail.

		The book became controversial due to its conflict with the religious belief about the creation of the world. However, in later years, it was embraced by all biologists. Darwin’s another book, “The Variation of Animals and Plants Under Domestication”, came out in 1868. It is considered to be his second most significant work. The book maintains that man, by selective breeding, could make rather different breeds of pigeons, dogs, and some species of plants also. His work also included “The Various Contrivances by which Orchids are Fertilised by Insects”, “Insectivorous Plants”, “The Power of Movement in Plants”, “Descent of Man”, and “The Formation of Vegetable Mould Through the Action of Worms”.
 </achievements>
 </item>


<item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>A.P.J. Abdul Kalam</name>
  <img>kalam_h</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=59gCGLDz7ww</video>
  <bdate>October 15, 1931, Rameswaram, India</bdate>
  <quote>Man needs his difficulties because they are necessary to enjoy success.</quote>
<!--   <info>Little did Jainulabdeen and Ashiamma know that their son would grow up to be the first citizen of India. An Indian scientist and administrator, Kalam served as the 11th President of India from 2002 until 2007. One amongst the most respected people of the country, Kalam has contributed immensely both as a scientist and as a president. His contribution at the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) has been immense. He was responsible for numerous projects such as Project Devil and Project Valiant and launch of the Rohini-1, besides developing missiles under the missions Agni and Prithvi. For the same, he has been popularly tagged as the "Missile Man of India". Kalam has been honored with great laurels and awards for his work by both the Government of India and other countries. Currently, Kalam serves as a visiting professor in various esteemed institutes and universities of India.</info> -->
 <info>APJ Abdul Kalam was born on 15 October 1931 at the South Indian state of Tamil Nadu and received honorary doctorates from about 30 universities globally. In the year 1981, the Government of India presented him the nation's highest civilian honor, the Padma Bhushan and then again, the Padma Vibhushan in 1990 and the Bharat Ratna in 1997. Before Kalam, there have been only two presidents - Sarvepalli Radhakrishnan and Zakir Hussain - to have received the Bharat Ratna before bring appointed to the highest office in India. 

	   Read on about the life history of Dr APJ Abdul Kalam, who's also the first scientist and bachelor to occupy the seat of the Rashtrapati Bhavan. His perspectives on important topics have been enunciated by him in the book 'India 2020'. It highlights the action plans that will help develop the country into a knowledge superpower by the time 2020. One thing for which he received ample kudos is his unambiguous statement that India needs to play a more assertive role in international relations. 

	   And Dr APJ Abdul Kalam regards his work on India's nuclear weapons program as a way to assert India's place as a future superpower. Even during his tenure as President, APJ Kalam took avid interest in the spheres of India's science and technology. He has even put forward a project plan for establishing bio-implants. He is also an ardent advocate of open source software over proprietary solutions to churn out more profits in the field of information technology in India.
 </info>
 <achievements>
     This eminent scientist and engineer has also served as the 11th President of India from the period 2002 to 2007. APJ Abdul Kalam is a man of vision, who is always full of ideas aimed at the development of the country. He firmly believes that India needs to play a more assertive role in international relations. 

	 Apart from being a notable scientist and engineer, Dr APJ Abdul Kalam served as the 11th President of India from the period 2002 to 2007. He is a man of vision, who is always full of ideas aimed at the development of the country and is also often also referred to as the Missile Man of India. People loved and respected Dr APJ Abdul Kalam so much during his tenure as President that was popularly called the People's President.

	 Dr.Kalam has been awarded Padma Bhushan in 1981, Padma Vibhushan in 1990 and BHARAT RATNA in 1997.
 </achievements>
 </item>


<item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Albert Einstein</name>
  <img>alberteinstein</img>
  <bdate>March 14, 1879, Ulm, Germany</bdate>
  <ddate>April 18, 1955, Princeton, New Jersey, United States</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-1Z2wi2uSA</video>
  <quote>The important thing is not to stop questioning. Curiosity has its own reason for existing.</quote>
<!--   <info>Do you fondly call the whiz kid in your class/ organization 'Einstein'? If yes, then you aren't the only one who does so. People around the world honor their friends and acquaintance with the title of 'Einstein' for the person's immaculate brilliance and genius mind. While there may be a lot of genius mind set at work to this date, only once in a century is Albert Einstein born. The 19th century not just witnessed the birth of Albert Einstein, but with it, the birth of modern physics. Rightly known as the Father of Modern Physics, Albert Einstein was, without a doubt, the most influential physicist of the 20th century. With his research and finding, Einstein created a revolution in the field of science. Amongst his numerous works: (a) the general theory of relativity, which provided a unified description of gravity as a geometric property of space and time, and (b) photoelectric effect that established the quantum theory within physics are the most important ones. During his lifetime, Einstein published more than 300 scientific papers, apart from 150 non-scientific works. He was the proud recipient of numerous awards, such as Nobel Prize in Physics, Copley Medal, Matteucci Medal and Max Planck medal. Other than these, he has also been credited by the Times magazine as the Person of the Century. Such was his contribution to mankind that his name Einstein has been made synonymous to being "genius".</info> -->
  <info>Albert Einstein was born at Ulm, in Württemberg, Germany, on March 14, 1879. Six weeks later the family moved to Munich, where he later on began his schooling at the Luitpold Gymnasium. Later, they moved to Italy and Albert continued his education at Aarau, Switzerland and in 1896 he entered the Swiss Federal Polytechnic School in Zurich to be trained as a teacher in physics and mathematics. In 1901, the year he gained his diploma, he acquired Swiss citizenship and, as he was unable to find a teaching post, he accepted a position as technical assistant in the Swiss Patent Office. In 1905 he obtained his doctor's degree.
  
        Einstein always appeared to have a clear view of the problems of physics and the determination to solve them. He had a strategy of his own and was able to visualize the main stages on the way to his goal. He regarded his major achievements as mere stepping-stones for the next advance.

		At the start of his scientific work, Einstein realized the inadequacies of Newtonian mechanics and his special theory of relativity stemmed from an attempt to reconcile the laws of mechanics with the laws of the electromagnetic field. He dealt with classical problems of statistical mechanics and problems in which they were merged with quantum theory: this led to an explanation of the Brownian movement of molecules. He investigated the thermal properties of light with a low radiation density and his observations laid the foundation of the photon theory of light.
 		
 		Albert Einstein received honorary doctorate degrees in science, medicine and philosophy from many European and American universities. During the 1920's he lectured in Europe, America and the Far East, and he was awarded Fellowships or Memberships of all the leading scientific academies throughout the world. He gained numerous awards in recognition of his work, including the Copley Medal of the Royal Society of London in 1925, and the Franklin Medal of the Franklin Institute in 1935.

		Einstein's gifts inevitably resulted in his dwelling much in intellectual solitude and, for relaxation, music played an important part in his life. He married Mileva Maric in 1903 and they had a daughter and two sons; their marriage was dissolved in 1919 and in the same year he married his cousin, Elsa Löwenthal, who died in 1936. He died on April 18, 1955 at Princeton, New Jersey.
  </info>
  <achievements>
      1. Einstein showed that absolute time had to be replaced by a new absolute: the speed of light. Einstein went against the grain and totally dismissed the "Old Physics." He envisioned a world where space and time are relative and the speed of light is absolute (at the time, it was believed that space and time were absolute and the speed of light was relative).

	  2. He asserted the equivalence of mass and energy, which would lead to the famous formula E=mc2

	  3. Einstein challenged the wave theory of light, suggesting that light could also be regarded as a collection of particles. This helped to open the door to a whole new world--that of quantum physics. For ideas in this paper, he won the Nobel Prize in 1921.

	  4. His paper concerning the Brownian motion of particles. With profound insight, Einstein blended ideas from kinetic theory and classical hydrodynamics to derive an equation for the mean free path of such particles as a function of the time.

	  5. Einstein showed how to calculate Avogadro's number and the size of molecules.

	  6. In 1910, Einstein answered a basic question: 'Why is the sky blue?' His paper on the phenomenon called critical opalescence solved the problem by examining the cumulative effect of the scattering of light by individual molecules in the atmosphere.

	  7. Einstein later published a paper in 1915 called "General Relativity." General Relativity took over when Special Relativity started to fail. Controversy started to rise when Einstein released his second paper called "General Relativity."

      8. In 1917, Einstein published a paper which uses general relativity to model the behavior of an entire universe. General relativity has spawned some of the weirdest, and most important results in modern astronomy.

	  9. Einstein recognized that there might be a problem with the classical notion of cause and effect. Given the peculiar, dual nature of quanta as both waves and particles, it might be impossible, he warns, to definitively tie effects to their causes.
  </achievements>
 </item>  
 
 <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Alfred Nobel</name>
  <img>nobel_hh</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <bdate>October 21, 1833, Stockholm, Sweden</bdate>
  <ddate>December 10, 1896, Sanremo, Italy</ddate>
  <discoveries>Dynamite</discoveries>
  <quote>If I have a thousand ideas and only one turns out to be good, I am satisfied.</quote>
  <info>Alfred Bernhard Nobel was a Swedish inventor, engineer and industrialist who had obtained a total of 355 patents in his lifetime. He was most well-known for inventing dynamite, and for developing some more powerful explosives and detonators to effectively ignite them. He built a network of almost a hundred factories all over the world to manufacture explosives and ammunition, and amassed a massive fortune from his businesses. In fact, at the time of his death, he was one of the wealthiest persons on the world. Since he was unmarried and childless, there were many speculations about the contents of his last will which he had signed on 27th November, 1895. The contents of his will caused a lot of disappointment to his much hopeful extended family as Nobel had left much of his wealth for the establishment of an international prize fund! As the inventor of dynamite, he had earned the sobriquet, 'The Merchant of Death' which deeply traumatized Nobel who was a pacifist at heart. He did not want to be remembered as the reason behind mass destruction after his death, and in order to redeem his posthumous reputation, he left the major portion of his wealth for the establishment of the Nobel Prizes to be awarded for eminence in five different fields, without any discrimination on basis of nationality.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PC-sN5lbfhE</video>
  <achievements>
		There had to be a solution to the problem on reducing the economic cost ofconstruction and make it efficient,quick,and safe by inventing a brand new explosive(Alfred Nobel’s Life and Work).The only explosive they had around that time was black powder,but nitroglycerin,a new liquid explosive invented by Ascanio Sobrero became very useful that had a bigger impact when ignited, although it was very dangerous to handle (Industry History). This man,Alfred Nobel wants to create a safer production to stabilize nitroglycerin, so it would not cause a lot of trouble.(‘’History of Dynamite’’).
  
		The reasons why he did the whole process because his father’s company had bankrupt in and they moved back to Sweden, while they rely on Alfred’s mother for money as she owned a grocery store.Alfred returns after he was studying nitroglycerin in France.Alfred Nobel went back to Sweden to work on the some experiments with nitroglycerin with his father(‘’Famous Scientists’’).In 1864,one terrible accident had changed his life. One of his experiments failed and it blew up a factory killing several people including his Emil,his younger brother.This sent Stockholm to ban this project from the city limits(‘’Alfred Nobel’s Life and Work’’).
 		
 		He never gave up. One day he moved his project to Lake Malaren in Sweden on a boat.This is where the development of dynamite had begun.He had discovered Kieselguhr, a fine sand a.k.a Diatomaceous Earth, are used for absorbing liquids(‘’Diatomaceous’’). but which can make nitroglycerin into a solid(‘’Alfred Nobel’s Life and Work’’).He combined kieselguhr with nitroglycerin with wood pulp so it could absorb kieselguhr into nitroglycerin, so it would make a paste-like mixture.Then sodium nitrate was added to enhance the strength of the explosion upon detonation(Britannica).It formed into rods and dynamite was born.These rods are quite convenient,because it can be put into drilling holes.It can release its energy by detonating by heat or force so he created a new blasting cap where it can blow up by lighting a fuse.(‘’History of Dynamite’’)
 		
 		His invention blew up people’s mind. Companies started to use dynamite and Nobel had companies in about 90 different places in more than 20 countries(‘’Alfred Nobel’s Life and Work’’).This newly invented explosive outmatched the old-fashioned black powder. It helped make way through tunnels,make roads,structuring bridges which is fast,efficient,and cost effective. It became so popular that it went through globally, all the way to America.In one terrible earthquake in 1906 in San Francisco caused a fire. And they tried to affected destroy buildings with dynamite so that the fire won’t spread. This shows that dynamite is useful in a worse case scenario.(‘’Industry History’’)
		
		Morally, it really depends. It is safer, more efficient and it also encourages construction work(‘’Alfred Nobel’s Life and Work’’). Although they are great things, they do impact human health.Dynamites contain a lot of chemicals and when they explode, there is a hot gas filled with chemicals that puts pressure and eats up all the oxygen surrounding.That would be a difficult environment to breath in(‘‘HowStuffWorks’’).
  </achievements>
 </item> 
 
 
 <item>
  <id>6</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>C. V. Raman</name>
  <img>cvraman</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <bdate>November 7, 1888, Thiruvanaikaval, India</bdate>
  <ddate>November 21, 1970, Bangalore, India</ddate>
  <discoveries>He was the first Indian scholar who studied wholly in India received the Nobel Prize.Raman effect</discoveries>
  <quote>The true wealth of a nation consists not in the stored- up gold but in the intellectual and physical strength of its people.</quote>
  <info>Chandrasekhara Venkata Raman was born at Tiruchirappalli in Southern India on November 7th, 1888. His father was a lecturer in mathematics and physics so that from the first he was immersed in an academic atmosphere. He entered Presidency College, Madras, in 1902, and in 1904 passed his B.A. examination, winning the first place and the gold medal in physics; in 1907 he gained his M.A. degree, obtaining the highest distinctions.
		
		His earliest researches in optics and acoustics - the two fields of investigation to which he has dedicated his entire career - were carried out while he was a student.
		
		Since at that time a scientific career did not appear to present the best possibilities, Raman joined the Indian Finance Department in 1907; though the duties of his office took most of his time, Raman found opportunities for carrying on experimental research in the laboratory of the Indian Association for the Cultivation of Science at Calcutta (of which he became Honorary Secretary in 1919).
		
		In 1917 he was offered the newly endowed Palit Chair of Physics at Calcutta University, and decided to accept it. After 15 years at Calcutta he became Professor at the Indian Institute of Science at Bangalore (1933-1948), and since 1948 he is Director of the Raman Institute of Research at Bangalore, established and endowed by himself. He also founded the Indian Journal of Physics in 1926, of which he is the Editor. Raman sponsored the establishment of the Indian Academy of Sciences and has served as President since its inception. He also initiated the Proceedings of that academy, in which much of his work has been published, and is President of the Current Science Association, Bangalore, which publishes Current Science (India).
		
		Some of Raman's early memoirs appeared as Bulletins of the Indian Associationfor the Cultivation of Science (Bull. 6 and 11, dealing with the "Maintenance of Vibrations"; Bull. 15, 1918, dealing with the theory of the musical instruments of the violin family). He contributed an article on the theory of musical instruments to the 8th Volume of the Handbuch der Physik, 1928. In 1922 he published his work on the "Molecular Diffraction of Light", the first of a series of investigations with his collaborators which ultimately led to his discovery, on the 28th of February, 1928, of the radiation effect which bears his name ("A new radiation", Indian J. Phys., 2 (1928) 387), and which gained him the 1930 Nobel Prize in Physics.
		
		Other investigations carried out by Raman were: his experimental and theoretical studies on the diffraction of light by acoustic waves of ultrasonic and hypersonic frequencies (published 1934-1942), and those on the effects produced by X-rays on infrared vibrations in crystals exposed to ordinary light. In 1948 Raman, through studying the spectroscopic behaviour of crystals, approached in a new manner fundamental problems of crystal dynamics. His laboratory has been dealing with the structure and properties of diamond, the structure and optical behaviour of numerous iridescent substances (labradorite, pearly felspar, agate, opal, and pearls).
		
		Among his other interests have been the optics of colloids, electrical and magnetic anisotropy, and the physiology of human vision.
		
		Raman has been honoured with a large number of honorary doctorates and memberships of scientific societies. He was elected a Fellow of the Royal Society early in his career (1924), and was knighted in 1929.
  </info>
  <achievements>
        C.V. Raman’s work in physics was influential in the growth of science in India. He was the recipient of the Nobel Prize for Physics (becoming the first Indian to win this honor) in 1930 for the discovery that when light traverses a transparent material, some of the light that is deflected changes in wavelength. This phenomenon was called “Raman Scattering” and is now more commonly known as the “Raman Effect”.
		
		He was the first Indian scholar who studied wholly in India received the Nobel Prize. 

		C.V. Raman is one of the most renowned scientists produced by India. His full name was Chandrasekhara Venkata Raman. For his pioneering work on scattering of light, C.V. Raman won the Nobel Prize for Physics in 1930. 

		His pioneering work also resulted in him becoming the member of Royal Society of London in 1924. He was awarded with the knight of the British Empire in 1929 by Great Britain.

		Raman also worked as the director and Physics professor at the Indian Institute of Sciences in Bangalore for two years. Some of his other pioneering works include experimental and theoretical studies on the light diffraction by acoustic waves of hypersonic and ultrasonic frequencies. He also studied the effects produced by X-rays in crystals exposed to ordinary light on infrared vibrations. In addition, he established the Raman Research Institute after independence in Bangalore, where he worked until his death in 1970.
  </achievements>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L0IlhgZjQp0</video>
 </item> 
 
  <item>
  <id>7</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Srinivasa Ramanujan</name>
  <img>srinivasaramanujan</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <bdate>December 22, 1887, Erode, India</bdate>
  <ddate>April 26, 1920, Chetput, Chennai, India</ddate>
  <discoveries>Mathematics</discoveries>
  <quote>An equation means nothing to me unless it expresses a thought of God.</quote>
  <info>Ramanujan belonged to a Brahman family, but his father was poor and served as a bookkeeper in the firm of a cloth merchant in Kumbakonam. At the age of seven, after two years in elementary school, he transferred to the high school at Kumbakonam. In 1897 he placed first in the Tanjore primary examination. Ramanujan early studied some trigonometry on his own; real enthusiasm for the subject arose in 1903, when he was able to borrow an English text, Carr’s Synopsis of Pure Mathematics. From then on, mathematics was nearly his only interest. He jotted down his results in a notebook which he carried with him and showed to people who were interested.

		Quiet and meditative, Ramanujan was very fond of numerical calculations and had an unusual memory for numbers. In 1904 he won a fellowship at Government College, Kumbakonam. His excessive devotion to mathematics and neglect of English, a fundamental subject, led to his failure to be promoted. He returned to the college after traveling but could not graduate. He briefly attended a college in Madras, then returned to Kumbakonam, where he again failed. For several years he had no definite occupation but continued to record his mathematical results.

		In 1909 Ramanujan married and was compelled to earn a living. He went to Ramaswami Aiyar, the founder of the Indian Mathematical Society, then deputy collector in the little town of Tirukkoyilur, to ask for a minor clerical job. He was sent on to Seshu Aayar, one of Ramanujan’s former teachers, and obtained a substitute office job for a few months. He was then recommended to Ramachaudra Rao, collector of Nellore, eighty miles north of Madras, who was interested in mathematics; he later described Ramanujan at the time of the interview:

		A short uncouth figure, stout, unshaved, not over-clean, with one conspicuous feature—shining eyes-walked in with a frayed notebook under his arm. He was miserably poor.—He opened his book and began to explain some of his discoveries. I saw quite at once that there was something out of the way; but my knowledge did not permit me to judge whether he talked sense or nonsense. Suspending judgment, I asked him to come over again, and he did. And then he had gauged my ignorance and shewed me some of his simpler results. These transcended existing books, and I had no doubt he was a remarkable man. Then, step by step, he led me to elliptic integrals and hypergeometric series and at last his theory of divergent series not yet announced to the world converted me. I asked him what he wanted. He said he wanted a pittance to live on so that he might pursue his researches.

		Rao was convinced that a job as a clerk was not the answer to Ramanujan’s troubles and sent him back to Madras, where Rao supported him for a while and tried unsuccessfully to get a fellowship for him. When this did not succeed, Ramanujan in 1912 found a job in the office of the Madras Port Trust. At this time he began his mathematical publication in the Journal of the Indian Mathematical Society. His first paper, “Some Properties of Bernoulli’s Numbers,” was followed by a number of brief communications on series and infinite products and a geometric approximate construction of p.

		Encouraged by influential friends interested in his mathematical work, Ramanujan began a correspondence with G. H. Hardy of Cambridge, one of the world’s foremost specialists in analytic number theory. In his first letter Ramanujan mentioned his investigations on the distribution of primes and then added more than 100 theorems he had found in various parts of mathematics. Hardy was duly impressed and invited Ramanujan to come to England but, being a Brahman, he had scruples about leaving India. Instead a two-year fellowship was arranged for him at the University of Madras.

		Hardy was disappointed and continued to attempt to persuade Ramanujan to come to Cambridge. When his colleague E. H. Neville lectured in Madras, he approached the young man and this time obtained his consent. Very favorable fellowship arrangements were made, and Ramanujan was admitted to Trinity College in 1914. He developed rapidly under the guidance of Hardy and Littlewood, who also helped him to publish his papers in English periodicals. Aside from the dozen papers in the Journal of the Indian Mathematical Society, questions proposed, and notes from the proceedings of meetings, Ramanujan published twenty-onepapers during his five-year stay in Europe, several of them in collaboration with Hardy.

		It was inevitable that a large portion of Ramanujan’s results from his notebooks consisted of rediscoveries; he had never had systematic training in mathematics or access to a good library. To quote Hardy: “What was to be done in the way of teaching him modern mathematics? The limitations of his knowledge were as startling as its profundity.” He worked with modular equations and theorems of complex multiplication, yet had no notion of doubly periodic functions; he worked with analytic number theory and had only the vaguest idea of what a function of a complex variable was. Most of the theorems in the notebooks were not proved in the standard sense but were only made plausible: “His ideas as to what constituted a mathematical proof were of the most shadowy description. All his results, new or old, right or wrong, had been arrived at by a process of mingled argument, intuition and induction, of which he was entirely unable to give any coherent account.” Ramanujan’s investigations on the distribution of primes suffered particularly from these weaknesses and therefore contributed little to the development of the general theory.

		Ramanujan’s first paper published in Europe, “Modular Equations and Approximations to p” contained a number of peculiar and very good approximations to p, many of them by means of square root expressions. Of greater systematic interest is his long memoir “Highly Composite Numbers,” in which he derived some important properties of these numbers. Ramanujan returned to the question of the average number of prime divisors of a number in a paper written with Hardy,’The Normal Number of Prime Factors of a Number n.”

		The part of Ramanujan’s work that stimulated most contributions from later mathematicians is probably his study of the partition of numbers into summands. From MacMahon’s extensive numerical calculations of the number p(n) of partitions of a number n, Ramanujan conjectured that these integers must have simple congruence properties with respect to small primes and their powers. He was able to prove some of these results by means of formulas from the theory of elliptic functions; others have been derived later. These papers by Ramanujan on partitions were followed by a joint paper with Hardy on the asymptotic value of p(n). Their result was remarkable, since not only did their formula give good approximations to the values already calculated but also seemed to give an exact expression for p(n); Rademacher later established that this was correct.

		Ramanujan’s other work comprised a variety of topics, mainly of a combinatorial nature. He wrote on the representation of integers as the sum of squares and on the lattice points inside a circle; in function theory he produced several papers on definite integrals, as well as on elliptic, hypergeometric, and modular functions.

		In 1917 Ramanujan fell ill, possibly with tuberculosis; and the remainder of his stay in England was spent in several sanatoriums. In 1918 he was elected a fellow of the Royal Society and in the same year a fellow of Trinity College. These high distinctions seemed to improve his health and stimulate his mathematical production. Nevertheless, since the English climate did not seem to be beneficial, it was decided to send him back to India. An annual allowance of £250 for five years was awarded him by the University of Madras, with prospects of a later professorship.

		Ramanujan returned to Madras in April 1919 in a precarious state of health. A difficult patient who refused medical aid, he went for a while to his home district but was prevailed upon to return to Madras for treatment. Until his last days he continued his mathematical research.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		Ramanujan went to Cambridge in 1914 and it helped him a lot but by that time his mind worked on the patterns on which it had worked before and he seldom adopted new ways. By then, it was more about intuition than argument. Hardy said Ramanujan could have become an outstanding mathematician if his skills had been recognized earlier. It was said about his talents of continued fractions and hypergeometric series that, “he was unquestionably one of the great masters.” It was due to his sharp memory, calculative mind, patience and insight that he was a great formalist of his days. But it was due to his some methods of working in the work analysis and theories of numbers that did not let him excel that much.

		He got elected as the fellow in 1918 at the Trinity College at Cambridge and the Royal Society. He departed from this world on April 26, 1920.
	
	    Ramanujan independently discovered results of Gauss, Kummer and others on hypergeometric series. Ramanujan's own work on partial sums and products of hypergeometric series have led to major development in the topic. His most famous work was on the number p(n) of partitions of an integer n into summands. 
 		
 		Srinivasa Ramanujan was a mathematician par excellence. He is widely believed to be the greatest mathematician of the 20th Century. Srinivasa Ramanujan made significant contribution to the analytical theory of numbers and worked on elliptic functions, continued fractions, and infinite series.
  </achievements>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rkqlrr43f9o</video>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>8</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Thomas Alva Edison</name>
  <img>thomasedison</img>
  <bdate>February 11, 1847, Milan, Ohio, United States</bdate>
  <ddate>October 18, 1931, West Orange, New Jersey, United States</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bc4qfMNSQ34</video>
  <quote>Genius is one percent inspiration, ninety-nine percent perspiration.</quote>
  <info>Thomas Alva Edison was the most prolific inventor in American history. He amassed a record 1,093 patents covering key innovations and minor improvements in wide range of fields, including telecommunications, electric power, sound recording, motion pictures, primary and storage batteries, and mining and cement technology. As important, he broadened the notion of invention to encompass what we now call innovation-invention, research, development, and commercialization-and invented the industrial research laboratory. Edison's role as an innovator is evident not only in his two major laboratories at Menlo Park and West Orange in New Jersey but in more than 300 companies formed worldwide to manufacture and market his inventions, many of which carried the Edison name, including some 200 Edison illuminating companies.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		The Edison Lamp

		Others before and in the same period with Edison toiled long and hard to produce a practical incandescent lamp.  The idea was not original with him, but it required the Edison genius to solve the difficult problems involved.

		Many persons tried to deprive Edison of the honor of having been the first to perfect a practical incandescent electric lamp, but they all met with failure.  Edison’s claim was to genuine to be set aside, even by the courts which, for one reason or another, might have been inclined to bias.
 		
 		Edison realized that the invention of a practical lamp alone was not enough to replace gas as the most-used means of lighting.  Therefore, his work on the electric light is even more astonishing, because in addition to perfecting a commercially practical lamp he also invented a ‘complete generation and distribution system, including dynamos, conductors, fuses, meters, sockets, and numerous other devices.  Of 1,097 United States patents granted to Edison during his lifetime – by far the greatest number ever granted to one individual – 356 dealt with electric lighting and the generation and distribution of electricity.
  
  
 		The ‘Edison Effect”

		The year 1883 was significant for Edison in that, by his discovery of what was to become known as the “Edison effect,” he pushed aside a veil of darkness behind which were to be found all the wonders of electronics.  Edison in this achievement discovered the previously unknown phenomenon by which an independent wire or plate, when placed between the legs of the filament in an electric bulb, serves as a valve to control the flow of current.  This discovery unearthed the fundamental principle on which rests the modern science of electronics.

		In that year, 1883, Edison filed a patent on an electrical indicator employing the “Edison effect,” the first application in the field of electronics.

		The facilities of Menlo Park were proving inadequate to meet the requirements of Edison’s amazing ability.  He began looking around for a place more suitable for his needs.  This he found in the little Essex County community of West Orange in northern New Jersey.  He gave the orders that set workmen to the task of building a new and greater research laboratory. 
  
 		The Motion Picture Camera

		Two things led Edison to the invention of the motion picture camera:  His idea that motion could be captured by having one camera that would take repeated pictures at high speed, and a new celluloid film developed by George Eastman for use in still photography that proved adaptable to Edison’s proposed camera.
  
  		No field of scientific endeavor seemed foreign to his talents.  When, in 1914, a shortage of carbolic acid developed because World War I had cut off European supplies, Edison quickly devised a method of making domestic carbolic acid and was producing a ton a day within a month.
  </achievements>
 </item>  
 
 <item>
  <id>9</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Yellapragada Subbarow</name>
  <img>subbarao</img>
  <bdate>January 12, 1895, Bhimavaram, India</bdate>
  <ddate>August 9, 1948, New York, United States</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3odh3Iucyko</video>
  <quote>You've probably never heard of Dr. Yellapragada SubbaRow,Yet because he lived you may live longe</quote>
  <info>Yellapragada Subbarao was born in a poor Telugu 6000 Niyogi Brahmin family in Bhimavaram district in Old Madras Presidency, now in West Godavari district, Andhra Pradesh. He was born as the fourth child amongst seven children to Y. Jagganatham and Y. Venkamma. Though his father worked as a revenue inspector, the family suffered from many hardships of poverty due to the loss of several of his close relatives at a young age. As such, his schooling at Rajahmundry went through a traumatic phase, leading to his completion of matriculation in the third attempt from Hindu High School in Madras. He attained his intermediate education from Presidency College and took admission in Madras Medical College, his education being financed by his friends and Kasturi Suryanarayana Murthy. He later went on to marry Murthy's daughter.
  
		With so many discoveries and developments to his credit, Subbarao never marketed his work and hence, was always left behind in terms of work recognition and appreciation. He always sat in the audience and had to be pushed to the stage by a colleague or a collaborator to take a bow as each of his researches was revealed to the public. Further, he was seen giving interviews to the press or visiting nations on lecture tours. When his colleague George Hitchings won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, along with Gertrude Elion, in 1988, he stated that some of the works initiated by Subbarao had to be rediscovered for the simple reason that his partner Fiske did not allow his contributions earn name and fame, probably out of jealousy. American Cyanamid honored Subbarao by naming a new fungus under his name "Subbaromyces splendens".
  </info>
 <achievements>
		Subbarao discovered many more antibiotics for a wide range of cures, other than the already discovered penicillin and streptomycin. His research led him to the discovery of polymyxin which is still used in cattle-feed. This led to laying the foundation for the isolation of vitamin B9, the antipernicious anemia factor, based on the work conducted by Lucy Wills in 1945. He applied different inputs given by Dr. Sidney Farber to develop an anti-cancer drug Methotrexate, one of the first cancer chemotherapy agents, which is still used worldwide. He was also credited with the discovery of drug Hetrazen, a cure for filariasis at Lederle. Today, this drug is the most widely used medicine for treating filariasis, including World Health Organization. Under his directorship, Benjamin Duggar gave birth to his discovery of the world's first tetracycline antibiotic, Aureomycin in the same year. This resulted as one of the largest distributed scientific experiments till date with American soldiers being asked to collect soil samples during World War II and deposit them at Lederle Laboratories for anti-bacterial agents from natural soil fungi. Another medicine that he discovered was Isonicotinic acid Hydrazide, an effective cure for tuberculosis.

		With so many discoveries and developments to his credit, Subbarao never marketed his work and hence, was always left behind in terms of work recognition and appreciation. He always sat in the audience and had to be pushed to the stage by a colleague or a collaborator to take a bow as each of his researches was revealed to the public. Further, he was seen giving interviews to the press or visiting nations on lecture tours. When his colleague George Hitchings won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine, along with Gertrude Elion, in 1988, he stated that some of the works initiated by Subbarao had to be rediscovered for the simple reason that his partner Fiske did not allow his contributions earn name and fame, probably out of jealousy. American Cyanamid honored Subbarao by naming a new fungus under his name "Subbaromyces splendens".
 </achievements>
 </item> 
 
 
 
 <item>
  <id>10</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Charles Babbage</name>
  <img>charles</img>
  <bdate>December 26, 1791, Teignmouth, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>October 18, 1871, Marylebone, United Kingdom</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mldLwKvT-M</video>
  <quote>The economy of human time is the next advantage of machinery in manufactures.</quote>
  <info>
		Charles Babbage was born in London Dec. 26, 1791, St. Stephan day, in London. He was son of Benjamin Babbage, a banking partner of the Praeds who owned the Bitton Estate in Teignmouth and Betsy Plumleigh Babbage. It was about 1808 when the Babbage family decided to move into the old Rowdens house, located in East Teignmouth, and Benjamin Babbage became a warden of the nearby church of St. Michael. 

		The father of Charles was a rich man, so it was possible for Charles to receive instruction from several elite schools and teachers during the course of his elementary education. He was about eight when he had to move to a country school to recover from a dangerous fever. His parents sentenced that his "brain was not to be taxed too much"; Babbage wrote: "this great idleness may have led to some of my childish reasonings." 
		Then, he joined King Edward VI Grammar School in Totnes, South Devon, a thriving comprehensive school that's still operative today, but his fragile health status forced him back to private teaching for a period. Then, he finally joined a 30-student closed number academy managed by Reverend Stephen Freeman. The academy had a big library, where Babbage used to study mathematics by himself, and learned to love it. He had two more personal tutors after leaving the academy. One was a clergyman of Cambridge, and about him Babbage said: "I fear I did not derive from it all the advantages that I might have done.". The other one was an Oxford tutor who teached Babbage the Classics, so that he could be accepted to Cambridge. 

		Babbage arrived at Trinity College, Cambridge in October 1810. He had a big culture - he knew Lagrange, Leibniz, Lacroix, Simpson... and he was seriously disappointed about the math programs available at Cambridge. So he, with J.Herschel, G.Peacock, and other friends, decided to form the Analytical Society. 

		When, in 1812, Babbage transferred to Peterhouse, Cambridge, he was the best mathematician; but he failed to graduate with honours. 
		He received an honorary degree later, without even being examinated, in 1814. 

		In 1814, Charles Babbage married Georgiana Whitmore at St. Michael's Church in Teignmouth, Devon. His father, for some reason, never gave his approvation. They lived in tranquility at 5 Devonshire Street, Portland Place, London. 
		Only Three of their 8 children became adult.
		Tragically, Charles' father, his wife and one of his sons all died in 1827.
  
  </info>
 <achievements>
		charles babbage received many honors and awards. In 1816, he was elected fellow of the royal society. He got his first gold medal from the astronomical society of london, and then received an honorary degree from the peter house. 
 </achievements>
 </item> 
 
  <item>
  <id>11</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Marie Curie</name>
  <img>marie</img>
  <bdate>November 7, 1867, Warsaw, Poland</bdate>
  <ddate>July 4, 1934, Passy, Haute-Savoie, France</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0vTRrZU-LKQ</video>
  <quote>Be less curious about people and more curious about ideas.</quote>
  <info>
		Marie Skłodowska-Curie was a Polish and naturalized-French physicist and chemist who conducted pioneering research on radioactivity. She was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize, the first person (and only woman) to win twice, the only person to win twice in multiple sciences, and was part of the Curie family legacy of five Nobel Prizes. She was also the first woman to become a professor at the University of Paris, and in 1995 became the first woman to be entombed on her own merits in the Panthéon in Paris.

		She was born Maria Salomea Skłodowska in Warsaw, in what was then the Kingdom of Poland, part of the Russian Empire. She studied at Warsaw's clandestine Floating University and began her practical scientific training in Warsaw. In 1891, aged 24, she followed her older sister Bronisława to study in Paris, where she earned her higher degrees and conducted her subsequent scientific work. She shared the 1903 Nobel Prize in Physics with her husband Pierre Curie and with physicist Henri Becquerel. She won the 1911 Nobel Prize in Chemistry.

		Her achievements included a theory of radioactivity , techniques for isolating radioactive isotopes, and the discovery of two elements, polonium and radium. Under her direction, the world's first studies were conducted into the treatment of neoplasms, using radioactive isotopes. She founded the Curie Institutes in Paris and in Warsaw, which remain major centres of medical research today. During World War I, she established the first military field radiological centres.

		While a French citizen, Marie Skłodowska Curie (she used both surnames) never lost her sense of Polish identity. She taught her daughters the Polish language and took them on visits to Poland. She named the first chemical element that she discovered – polonium, which she first isolated in 1898 – after her native country.

		Curie died in 1934 at the sanatorium of Sancellemoz (Haute-Savoie), France, due to aplastic anemia brought on by exposure to radiation – including carrying test tubes of radium in her pockets during research and her World War I service in mobile X-ray units created by her.	
  
  
  </info>
 <achievements>
		Marie Curie was famous for being an accomplished Chemist. She worked in the field of radiation. Marie Curie was the first person to discover radiation in 1898. Marie 

		Curie identified there was radiation in many things.

		She was the first scientist to use the term radioactive, to describe elements that give off radiations as their nuclei break down.

		In 1903 Marie Curie was awarded the Nobel Prize in Physics for the discovery of radioactive elements. Marie Curie became the first woman to win the Nobel Prize.

		She was again awarded the Nobel Prize in 1911, this time in chemistry, for her work in radium and radium compounds. This was an important achievement, as no one had ever been awarded a second Nobel Prize, made even more remarkable as women were not commonly involved in this sort of work.

		In 1914 Marie Curie was further recognised by being appointed head of the Paris Institute of Radium. She then went on to help found the Curie Institute.

		Marie Curie died on 4 July 1934 of an illness caused by excess exposure to radiation.
		
		
 </achievements>
 </item> 

   <item>
  <id>12</id>
  <type>Science &amp; Technology</type>
  <name>Steve Jobs</name>
  <img>jobs</img>
  <bdate>February 24, 1955, San Francisco, California, United States</bdate>
  <ddate>October 5, 2011, Palo Alto, California, United States</ddate>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UF8uR6Z6KLc</video>
  <quote>Everyone here has the sense that right now is one of those moments when we are influencing the future.</quote>
  <info>
		Steven Paul "Steve" Jobs was an American entrepreneur,marketer,and inventor, who was the co-founder, chairman, and CEO of Apple Inc. Through Apple, he is widely recognized as a charismatic and design-driven pioneer of the personal computer revolution and for his influential career in the computer and consumer electronics fields, transforming "one industry after another, from computers and smartphones to music and movies." Jobs also co-founded and served as chief executive of Pixar Animation Studios; he became a member of the board of directors of The Walt Disney Company in 2006, when Disney acquired Pixar. Jobs was among the first to see the commercial potential of Xerox PARC's mouse-driven graphical user interface, which led to the creation of the Apple Lisa and, a year later, the Macintosh. He also played a role in introducing the LaserWriter, one of the first widely available laser printers, to the market.

		After a power struggle with the board of directors in 1985, Jobs left Apple and founded NeXT, a computer platform development company specializing in the higher-education and business markets. In 1986, he acquired the computer graphics division of Lucasfilm, which was spun off as Pixar. He was credited in Toy Story (1995) as an executive producer. He served as CEO and majority shareholder until Disney's purchase of Pixar in 2006. In 1996, after Apple had failed to deliver its operating system, Copland, Gil Amelio turned to NeXT Computer, and the NeXTSTEP platform became the foundation for the Mac OS X. Jobs returned to Apple as an advisor, and took control of the company as an interim CEO. Jobs brought Apple from near bankruptcy to profitability by 1998.

		As the new CEO of the company, Jobs oversaw the development of the iMac, iTunes, iPod, iPhone, and iPad, and on the services side, the company's Apple Retail Stores, iTunes Store and the App Store. The success of these products and services provided several years of stable financial returns, and propelled Apple to become the world's most valuable publicly traded company in 2011. The reinvigoration of the company is regarded by many commentators as one of the greatest turnarounds in business history.

		In 2003, Jobs was diagnosed with a pancreas neuroendocrine tumor. Though it was initially treated, he reported a hormone imbalance, underwent a liver transplant in 2009, and appeared progressively thinner as his health declined. On medical leave for most of 2011, Jobs resigned in August that year, and was elected Chairman of the Board. He died of respiratory arrest related to the tumor on October 5, 2011.

		Jobs received a number of honors and public recognition for his influence in the technology and music industries. He has been referred to as "legendary", a "futurist" and a "visionary", and has been described as the "Father of the Digital Revolution," a "master of innovation," "the master evangelist of the digital age" and a "design perfectionist."
  
  </info>
 <achievements>
		During his life, he received several awards including National Medal of Technology and Jefferson Award for Public Service.

		He was inducted into California Hall of Fame in 2007. Same year, he was named the most powerful person in business by Fortune magazine.
 
		In 2009, Fortune magazine named him as the CEO of the decade. Following year, he ranked at No 17 in Forbes list of The World's Most Powerful People.

		In 2010, he was named person of the year by Financial Times.

   </achievements>
 </item> 
  
  
</menu>
 


