<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>
<item>
  <id>0</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Dhyan Chand</name>
  <img>dhyanchand</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Kp5BIHbZJwU</video>
  <bdate>August 29, 1905, Allahabad, India</bdate> 
  <ddate> December 3, 1979, Delhi, India</ddate>  
  <quote>This is not a game of hockey, but magic. Dhyan Chand is in fact the magician of hockey.</quote>
  <info>Major Dhyan ‘Chand’ Singh
		August 29, 1905 – December 3, 1979
		Widely regarded as the greatest hockey player of all time!
		
		Dhyan Chand is to hockey what Bradman is to cricket, Mohammed Ali to boxing and Pele to football!
		Legendary center-forward!
		Won 3 Olympic gold medals
		Scored more than 400 goals during his international career.
		Awarded Padma Bhushan in 1956.
		Born in Prayag, Allahabad in Uttar Pradesh.
		His father Sameshwar Dutt Singh was in the Indian Army and played hockey in the army.
		Had to terminate his education after class six due to frequesnt transfers of father.
		
		Young Dhyan had no serious inclination towards sports, though he loved wrestling.
		He did not play any hockey worth mentioning before he joined the Army.
		He occasionally indulged in casual games in Jhansi with his friends.
		Chand joined the Indian Army at the age of 16, in 1922 .
		Subedar-Major Bale Tiwari noticed his dribbling skills. He became his mentor and laid the foundations of his game.
		Between 1922 and 1926, Chand exclusively played the army hockey tournaments and the regimental games.
		Chand was ultimately selected for the Indian Army team which was to tour New Zealand.
		The team won 18 matches, drew 2 and lost only 1, receiving praises from all spectators. Returning to India, Chand was immediately promoted to Lance Naik.
  </info>
  <achievements>
      	Won 3 gold medals in Olympic games .Awarded the Padma Bhushan in 1956. 

		Dhyan Chand Singh was an Indian Hockey player, and considered to be the all time greatest player the game of Hockey has ever seen the world over. He has probably been the only Indian player ever in any sport which skills so high that generated a number of myths about his abilities as a Hockey player. 

  </achievements>
</item>


<item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Sachin Tendulkar</name>
  <img>sachin</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83oNPFZSJik</video>
  <bdate> April 24, 1973, Mumbai, India</bdate> 
  <quote>Every individual has his own style, his own way of presenting himself on and off the field.</quote>
  <info>Sachin Tendulkar was born April 24, 1973, in Bombay, India. Given his first cricket bat at the age 11, Tendulkar was just 16 when he became India's youngest Test cricketer. In 2005 he became the first cricketer to score 35 centuries (100 runs in a single inning) in Test play. In 2007 Tendulkar reached another major milestone, becoming the first player to record 15,000 runs in one-day international play. Considered by many to be the greatest cricket player of all time, Sendulkar took home the World Cup with his team in 2011 and retired from the sport two years later.
  
		Tendulkar received the Arjuna Award in 1994 for his outstanding sporting achievement, the Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna award in 1997, India's highest sporting honour, and the Padma Shri and Padma Vibhushan awards in 1999 and 2008, respectively, India's fourth and second highest civilian awards. After a few hours of his final match on 16 November 2013, the Prime Minister's Office announced the decision to award him the Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian award.He is the youngest recipient to date and the first ever sportsperson to receive the award.He also won the 2010 Sir Garfield Sobers Trophy for cricketer of the year at the ICC awards.In 2012, Tendulkar was nominated to the Rajya Sabha, the upper house of the Parliament of India.He was also the first sportsperson and the first person without an aviation background to be awarded the honorary rank of group captain by the Indian Air Force.In 2012, he was named an Honorary Member of the Order of Australia.

		In December 2012, Tendulkar announced his retirement from ODIs.He retired from Twenty20 cricket in October 2013 and subsequently announced his retirement from all forms of cricket,retiring on 16 November 2013 after playing his 200th and final Test match, against the West Indies in Mumbai's Wankhede Stadium. Tendulkar played 664 international cricket matches in total, scoring 34,357 runs.
</info>
<achievements>
		National honours

		1994 – Arjuna Award, by the Government of India in recognition of his outstanding achievement in sports.
		1997–98 – Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna, India's highest honour given for achievement in sports.
		1999 – Padma Shri, India's fourth highest civilian award.
		2001 – Maharashtra Bhushan Award, Maharashtra State's highest Civilian Award.
		2008 – Padma Vibhushan, India's second highest civilian award.
		2014 – Bharat Ratna, India's highest civilian award.

		Other honours

		1997 – Wisden Cricketer of the Year.
		2002 – In commemorating Tendulkar's feat of equalling Don Bradman's 29 centuries in Test Cricket, automotive company Ferrari invited him to its paddock in Silverstone on the eve of the British Grand Prix on 23 July, to receive a Ferrari 360 Modena from the F1 world champion Michael Schumacher.
		2003 – Player of the tournament in 2003 Cricket World Cup.
		2004, 2007, 2010 – ICC World ODI XI.
		2009, 2010, 2011 – ICC World Test XI.
		2010 – Outstanding Achievement in Sport and the Peoples Choice Award at The Asian Awards in London.
		2010 – Wisden Leading Cricketer in the World.
		2010 – ICC Award-Sir Garfield Sobers trophy for cricketer of the year.
		2010 – LG People's Choice Award.
		2010 – Made an Honorary group captain by the Indian Air Force.
		2011 – BCCI Cricketer of the Year award.
		2011 – Castrol Indian Cricketer of the Year award.
		2012 – Wisden India Outstanding Achievement award.
		2012 – Honorary Life Membership of Sydney Cricket Ground (SCG)
		2012 – Honorary Member of the Order of Australia, given by the Australian government.
		2013 – Indian Postal Service released a stamp of Tendulkar and he became the second Indian after Mother Teresa to have such stamp released in their lifetime.
</achievements>
</item>

<item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Pele</name>
  <img>pele</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T7HFq1gKeUU</video>
  <bdate>October 23, 1940, Três Corações, Minas Gerais, Brazil</bdate>
  <quote>Enthusiasm is everything. It must be taut and vibrating like a guitar string.</quote>
  <info>Pele is the most iconic footballer of the twentieth Century. He epitomised the flair, joy and passion the Brazilians bought to the game.

		Pele’s career spanned throughout the 1950s, 1960s and 1970s.

		In his early career, the young and unknown Pele helped inspire Brazil to victory in the 1958 World Cup. In 1962, Brazil retained the World Cup. In 1966, Brazil were hot favourites, but, lost out to the home nation England.

		His crowing glory was the Brazilian victory in the 1970 World Cup in Mexico. In this world cup, some of the football played by Brazil and Pele was widely considered to the greatest in the history of the game. Brazil won the final 4-1 against Italy; it was a genuine advertisement for the ‘beautiful game’ and a fitting pinnacle of Pele’s international career.

		Pele went on to score over 1,000 goals in professional games. (The 1000th goal coming as a penalty in the US league sparking celebrations around the world). His strike rate in international games was one of the highest ever. In 92 appearances, he scored 77 goals.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		Pele went on to lead Brazil in two more World Cup wins and play in another on top of that. This made him the only player to win three world cups, and one of the few players to play in four different World Cups!

		Also, he scored 1281 goals in 1363 matches over the course of his career, making him FIFA's most prolific scorer!

		On top of that, he set a record of 12 goals scored in one world cup, a record that was recently broken by another Brazilian named Ronaldo

		Those are some of Pele's biggest accomplishments, though they are by no means all that he did.
  </achievements>
 </item>

<item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Muhammad Ali</name>
  <img>muhammad_ali</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ANciqN3lydI</video>
  <bdate>January 17, 1942</bdate>
  <quote>He who is not courageous enough to take risks will accomplish nothing in life.</quote>
  <info>Muhammad Ali was one of America’s greatest 20th century boxers and athletes. Muhammad Ali was born Cassius Clay in Louisville, Kentucky. He started fighting at the age of 12 after his bicycle was stolen. Under the guidance of Joe Martin, Clay became an explosive boxer and won six Kentucky Gold Gloves during high school. In 1960, Clay won a gold medal in the Olympics at Rome, Italy.
  
		In 1965, Clay joined the Nation of Islam and changed his name to Muhammad Ali. Ali defended his championship for the next several years, winning many matches with a breathtaking combination of speed and power. In 1967, however Ali was stripped of his championship for refusing to fight in the Vietnam War. Ali immediately became a controversial figure, and was the subject of outrage for many Americans. Although Ali lost his title to Joe Frazier in 1971, he cemented his title as “The Greatest” by outdueling George Foreman in 1974 in “The Rumble in the Jungle”. In 1975, Ali defeated Joe Frazier in “The Thrilla in Manila”. In one of the best fights in boxing history, Ali won by TKO after the 14th round. In 1981, Ali retired with a career record of 56-5, with 37 knockouts.
  
		In 1984, he was diagnosed with Parkinson’s Disease, which would eventually confine him to a wheelchair and make it hard for him to communicate.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		1959	National Golden Gloves Light Heavyweight Champion
		1959	National Amateur Athletic Union champion
		1960	National Golden Gloves Light Heavyweight Champion
		1960	National Amateur Athletic Union champion
		1960	Gold medal, Rome Olympics, light-heavyweight boxing
		1964-67	World Heavyweight Champion
		1970	Dr. Martin Luther King Memorial Award
		1974	Sportsman of the Year, Sports Illustrated
		1974	Fighter of the Year, Boxing Writers Association
		1974-78	World Heavyweight Champion
		1978-79	World Heavyweight Champion
		1979	Honorary Doctorate of Humane Letters, Texas Southern Univesity
		1979	Street named after him in Louisville, Kentucky
		1985	Recognized for long, meritorious service, World Boxing Association
		1987	Elected to Boxing Hall of Fame
		1990	Inducted into International Boxing Hall of Fame
		1996	Lights Olympic torch, Atlanta
		1997	Arthur Ashe Award for Courage, ESPN
		1997	Essence Living Legend Award
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Carl Lewis</name>
  <img>carllewis</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OhKI7sH0O20</video>
  <bdate>July 1, 1961, Birmingham, Alabama, United States</bdate>
  <quote>The trials on the road to world harmony are no greater than the courage of those who accept the challenge.</quote>
  <info>Carl Lewis was born in Birmingham, Alabama, US on 1st July 1961. He become one of the greatest track and field stars of al time. His career spanned from 1979 to 1996 and included nine Olympic gold medals.

		His performance at the 1984 Olympics earned him 4 Gold medals in the 100m, 200m, Long Jump and 4*100 metre relay – an achievement equalling that of Jesse Owens in the 1936 Olympics.

		He has been voted Sportsman of the Century by the International Olympic Committee IOC.
  </info>
  <achievements>
 		In his active years, he was the undisputed athlete of track and field, his medals standing as a testimony of the same. While his Olympic record stands at 9 gold and 1 silver, his World Championship medals tally include: 8 gold, 1 silver and 1 bronze. At the Pan American and Goodwill Games, he won 2 and 3 gold medals respectively.  

		Publications around the world have honoured him with various titles including ‘Sportman of the Century’, ‘World Athlete of the Century’ and ‘Olympian of the Century’. 

  </achievements>
 </item>
 
  <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Jackie Joyner-Kersee</name>
  <img>jackie</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Z-QfDiV2XA</video>
  <bdate>March 3, 1962, East St. Louis, Illinois, United States</bdate>
  <quote>It's better to look ahead and prepare, than to look back and regret.</quote>
  <info>Joyner showed great enthusiasm for athletics early on, and as a teenager she won the first of four consecutive National Junior Pentathlon championships. In high school she was a determined student and athlete, graduating near the top of her class and competing on the school’s volleyball, basketball, and track teams. As a junior, she set the Illinois high-school girls’ long jump record at 6.68 metres (20 feet 7.5 inches). Her high-school success led to a scholarship to the University of California, Los Angeles, where she initially focused on basketball and the long jump.
  
		Joyner-Kersee’s best heptathlon events were the long jump, 100-metre hurdles, 200-metre run, and high jump. She often competed in single events, particularly the long jump, in which she tied the world record (7.45 metres [24 feet 5.5 inches]) in 1987 and won the gold medal in 1988 and the bronze in 1992. After the 1996 Olympics, Joyner-Kersee played professional basketball with the Richmond Rage; she left the team midway through her first season to compete in the long jump indoors. In 1997 she published A Kind of Grace: The Autobiography of the World’s Greatest Female Athlete.
  </info>
 <achievements>
		1974-78	Wins four consecutive national junior pentathlon championships
		1984	Silver medal, Olympic heptathlon
		1985	Sets U.S. record in long jump
		1986	Sets two world records in heptathlon
		1986	Sullivan Award for Best Amateur Athlete; Jesse Owens Award; Track and Field Athlete of the Year
		1987	McDonald's Amateur Athlete of the Year
		1988	Olympic gold medals in heptathlon and long jump
		1989	Honorary doctorate, University of Missouri
		1992	Olympic gold medal, heptathlon; Olympic bronze medal, long jump
		1996	Olympic bronze medal, long jump
		1998	Gold medal, heptathlon, Goodwill Games

 </achievements>
 
 </item>
 
   <item>
  <id>6</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Ayrton Senna</name>
  <img>ayrton</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6nS8W3b3wvY</video>
  <bdate>March 21, 1960, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil</bdate>
  <ddate>May 1, 1994, Imola, Italy</ddate>  
  <quote>On a given day, a given circumstance, you think you have a limit.</quote>
  <info>Ayrton Senna da Silva (March 21, 1960 – May 1, 1994), better known as Ayrton Senna, was a Brazilian Formula One driver who won the world championship three times, in 1988, 1990 and in 1991. He is widely regarded as one of the greatest and most skilful drivers of all time.

		He died in 1994, at the peak of his motor racing career in a tragic accident at Imola, San Marino.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		Ayrton Senna’s extraordinary feats at the wheel of a racing car yielded three world championship titles and 41 grand prix victories. He was probably the greatest exponent of the flat-out qualifying lap the sport has ever seen, taking 65 pole positions in 162 races.
	
		These achievements alone ensured his name would be forever writ large in the history books long before the tragic circumstances of his death while leading the 1994 San Marino Grand Prix.

		Senna first came to the attention of Formula One teams in 1983 as he was on his way to winning the British Formula Three championship. Williams were first to test the 23-year-old, and McLaren and Brabham also put him in their cars.

		At the latter Nelson Piquet bristled at the prospect of being paired with another bright Brazilian talent and moved to block Senna’s arrival. Neither Williams nor McLaren were prepared to offer him a race seat for the coming season, so Senna secured a drive at the tiny Toleman outfit, who were entering their fourth season and were yet to finish a race higher than fourth place.

		That changed soon after Senna’s arrival. In dreadful conditions at Monaco he guided his TG184 between the barriers on a near-flooded track whole seconds faster than the front runners. He was gaining on race leader – and future arch-rival – Alain Prost when the race was controversially red-flagged.

		To that second place he added two more podium finishes before the end of the season. But he also incurred the wrath of Toleman boss Alex Hawkridge, who barred Senna from racing at Monza after his driver broke their contract to sign a deal with Lotus.

		Again the results came quickly. Just two races into his Lotus career Senna became a race winner. Again he prevailed in dire conditions, this time at Estoril in Portugal, finishing a minute clear of his rivals. Seven pole positions that year underlined his status as the sport’s foremost qualifier.

		But on race days the reliability of the Lotus and the fuel consumption of its Renault engine was often found wanting. Nonetheless he led the 1986 championship in its early stages and remained in the hunt until late in the year.
  </achievements>
 </item>

<item>
  <id>7</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Milkha Singh</name>
  <img>milkhasingh</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DYXH8SzWKck</video>
  <bdate>November 20, 1935, Govindpura, Pakistan</bdate> 
  <quote>There is no joy in competition if it is to be unfair.</quote>
  <info>Milkha Singh has been an Indian Athlete, and considered to be one of the greatest Athletes the nation has ever produced. Also, nicknamed as the Flying Sikh, Milkha has been the only Indian Athlete till date to have broken an Olympic Record, still he lost the Bronze Medal in the 400m event at Rome Olympic Games 1960 by just 0.1 seconds.
		
		Probably the best period during Milkha’s career as an Athlete arrived between the year 1958 and 1960. He won Gold Medals in both 200m and 400m events at the Tokyo Asian Games 1958, clocking 21.6 seconds and 47 seconds respectively. At the Cardiff Commonwealth Games held the same year, he improved his 400m timing to 46.16 seconds, and grabbed a Gold Medal again. 
		
		Honoring the incredible and hitherto the best performance by any Indian Athlete that Milkha Singh delivered throughout his sports career, he was bestowed upon the Padma Shri award (1958) and the Arjuna Award by the Government of India.
</info>
<achievements>
		Milkha Singh has been an Indian Athlete, and considered to be one of the greatest Athletes the nation has ever produced. Also, nicknamed as the Flying Sikh, Milkha has been the only Indian Athlete till date to have broken an Olympic Record, still he lost the Bronze Medal in the 400m event at Rome Olympic Games 1960 by just 0.1 seconds. 

		Won the 200 and 400 meters events in the 1956 Tokyo Asian Games
		Won the 400 meters at the 1958 Cardiff Commonwealth Games
		Broke the Olympic record for the 400 meters event while finishing fourth in the 1960 Rome Olympic Games

</achievements>
</item>

<item>
  <id>8</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Viswanathan Anand</name>
  <img>vishyanand</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ny9LL4YAJc0</video>
  <bdate> December 11, 1969, Mayiladuthurai, India</bdate> 
  <quote>There is always the risk of being over-confident when you are preparing to face a weaker player.</quote>
  <info>Vishwanathan Anand a young Indian boy used to religiously solve almost all the chess puzzles and theories aired by local Philippines T V stations in the late 70s. This boy used to win almost every time. His winning streak led to the studios calling him up and asking him not to participate so that others also got a chance. This boy was none other than the Indian Chess Wizard, Vishwanathan Anand.
  
		Vishwanathan Anand was the youngest Asian to win the International Master's Title at the age of fifteen. At sixteen he became the National Chess Champion; at eighteen India's First Grandmaster. In 1987, Vishy Anand became the first Asian to win the World Junior Chess Championship. In 1992, he won the formidable Reggio Emilia Tournament. Anand was the runner up to Kasparov in World Championship final in 1995. He defeated Kasparov in the rapid chess tournament in September 1996 and Karpov in June1997 in Hamburg Rapid Chess tournament. 

		In July 1999, Anand outplayed the most popular chess software programme, Fritz. Subsequently, Viswanathan Anand became the first Asian to win the World Chess Championship title. Anand won the world title on 24th December 2000, defeating Spain's Alexei Shirov at Teheran. For his outstanding performance and achievements Anand has received many awards; the Arjuna Award for Outstanding Indian Sportsman in 1985, Padmashree, National Citizens Award and Soviet Land Nehru Award in 1987. Viswanathan Anand was also awarded the prestigious Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award. Anand has also won the coveted Chess Oscars in 1997, 1998 and 2004.
  </info>
  <achievements>
		Viswanathan Anand been the epitome of chess in India and has gained worldwide recognition. In a glorious career spanning 25 years (and still counting), Anand has taken Indian chess to new heights. He has registered success in both the national and the international levels and has been entitled to a number of prestigious awards, for his excellence in chess. Born on 11 December 1969 in Chennai, Tamil Nadu, Viswanathan Anand is the role model for the aspiring chess players of India and has proved to be the prominent figure in the field of the sport, since the beginning of his career. 

		Became India's first Grandmaster in 1988
		Became the first Indian to win the FIDE World Chess Championship in 2000
		Won , the Chess Oscar many times
		World Chess Champion in 2007 and 2008

  </achievements>
</item>

<!--  
<item>
  <id>10</id>
  <type>Sports</type>
  <name>Sushil Kumar</name>
  <img>sushilkumar</img>
  <audio></audio>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DBI24NT1tIQ</video>
  <bdate>May 26, 1983</bdate> 
  <quote></quote>
  <info>Sushil Kumar led the Indian contingent at the 2012 London Summer Olympic Games and was India's flag bearer for the London Olympics opening ceremony on July 27.
 
		Sushil Kumar is an Indian wrestler who won the bronze medal in the Men's 66kg Freestyle Wrestling event at the 2008 Beijing Olympics. Kumar defeated Leonid Spiridonov of Kazakhstan in the repechage round to win the bronze.
 
		This was the second medal for India at the Beijing Olympics after shooter Abhinav Bindra claimed the first ever individual Olympic gold medal for the country in the 10 m Air Rifle event. This was also the second medal for India in wrestling, and the first since K D Jadhav's bronze medal at the 1952 Helsinki Olympic Games.
  </info>
</item>
 -->
<!--  <item> -->
<!--   <id>11</id> -->
<!--   <type>Sports</type> -->
<!--   <name>Kapil Dev</name> -->
<!--   <img>kapil</img> -->
<!--   <audio></audio> -->
<!--   <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=78sh10Bz_YY</video> -->
<!--   <bdate>January 6, 1959, Chandigarh, India</bdate>  -->
<!--   <quote>When you have to work, work with a smile.</quote> -->
<!--   <info>Considered to be one of the greatest cricketing all-rounders of all time, Kapil Dev is a former Indian cricketer best known for leading his team to a World Cup victory in 1983. Confident, charismatic and highly skilled, he was the Indian team's main strike bowler for the major part of his career. During his heydays he used to bamboozle batsmen with his prodigious swing. Dev was great not just with the ball; he was equally talented with the bat too. An expert at hooking and driving, he often provided India with the crucial runs needed to win a match even if the top-order failed to score. Born into a middle-class family in Haryana he became interested in cricket at a young age. He played for the Haryana cricket team at the beginning of his career eventually making his way into the national team, thanks to his aggressive play and high energy level. He cemented his place in the Indian team with his impressive performances and was soon made the captain. It was under his leadership that India went on to win the 1983 World Cup in spite of being the underdogs. -->
<!-- </info> -->
<!-- </item> -->
 </menu>


