<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<menu>

 <item>
  <id>0</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Mother Teresa</name>
  <img>teresa</img>
  <bdate>August 26, 1910, Skopje, Republic of Macedonia</bdate>
  <ddate>September 5, 1997, Kolkata,  India</ddate>  
<!--   <audio>http://anafiles.dreamhosters.com/mp3/MotherTeresa-1979NobelPeacePrizeSpeech.mp3</audio> -->
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>Love begins at home, and it is not how much we do... but how much love we put in that action.</quote>
  <info>Mother Teresa was born Agnes Gonxha Bojaxhiu in Skopje*, Macedonia, on August 26**, 1910. Her family was of Albanian descent. At the age of twelve, she felt strongly the call of God. She knew she had to be a missionary to spread the love of Christ. At the age of eighteen she left her parental home in Skopje and joined the Sisters of Loreto, an Irish community of nuns with missions in India. After a few months' training in Dublin she was sent to India, where on May 24, 1931, she took her initial vows as a nun. From 1931 to 1948 Mother Teresa taught at St. Mary's High School in Calcutta, but the suffering and poverty she glimpsed outside the convent walls made such a deep impression on her that in 1948 she received permission from her superiors to leave the convent school and devote herself to working among the poorest of the poor in the slums of Calcutta. Although she had no funds, she depended on Divine Providence, and started an open-air school for slum children. Soon she was joined by voluntary helpers, and financial support was also forthcoming. This made it possible for her to extend the scope of her work.
		On October 7, 1950, Mother Teresa received permission from the Holy See to start her own order, "The Missionaries of Charity", whose primary task was to love and care for those persons nobody was prepared to look after. In 1965 the Society became an International Religious Family by a decree of Pope Paul VI.
		Today the order comprises Active and Contemplative branches of Sisters and Brothers in many countries. In 1963 both the Contemplative branch of the Sisters and the Active branch of the Brothers was founded. In 1979 the Contemplative branch of the Brothers was added, and in 1984 the Priest branch was established.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sBVVvOSbcLU</video> 
  <achievements>
		Mother Teresa was one of the great servants of humanity. She was an Albanian Catholic nun who came to India and founded the Missionaries of Charity in Kolkata. Later on Mother Teresa attained Indian citizenship. Her selfless work among the poverty-stricken people of Kolkata (Calcutta) is an inspiration for people all over the world and she was honored with Nobel Prize for her work.
		
		For her unwavering commitment and unflinching love and compassion that she devoutly shared, the Government of India honoured her with Padma Shri, Jawaharlal Nehru Award for International Understanding and Bharat Ratna, India’s highest civilian award.  
		
		In 1962, she was honoured with Ramon Magsaysay Award for International Understanding, for her merciful cognizance of the abject poor of a foreign land, in whose service she led a new congregation.  
		
		In 1971, she was awarded the first Pope John XXIII Peace Prize for her work with the poor, display of Christian charity and efforts for peace.  
		
		In 1979, Mother Teresa was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize, "for work undertaken in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace."  
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>1</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Florence Nightingale</name>
  <img>florencenightingale</img>
  <bdate>May 12, 1820, Florence, Italy</bdate>
  <ddate>August 13, 1910, Park Lane, London, United Kingdom</ddate>  
<!--   <audio>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/the-voice-of-florence-nightingale/</audio> -->
  <audio></audio>
  <quote>I attribute my success to this - I never gave or took any excuse.
  </quote>
  <info>Florence Nightingale, was a celebrated English social reformer and statistician, and the founder of modern nursing. She came to prominence while serving as a nurse during the Crimean War, where she tended to wounded soldiers. She was known as "The Lady with the Lamp" after her habit of making rounds at night.

		Early 21st century commentators have asserted Nightingale's achievements in the Crimean War had been exaggerated by the media at the time, to satisfy the public's need for a hero, but her later achievements remain widely accepted. In 1860, Nightingale laid the foundation of professional nursing with the establishment of her nursing school at St Thomas' Hospital in London. It was the first secular nursing school in the world, now part of King's College London. The Nightingale Pledge taken by new nurses was named in her honour, and the annual International Nurses Day is celebrated around the world on her birthday. Her social reforms include improving healthcare for all sections of British society, improving healthcare and advocating better hunger relief in India, helping to abolish laws regulating prostitution that were over-harsh to women, and expanding the acceptable forms of female participation in the workforce.

		Nightingale was a prodigious and versatile writer. In her lifetime much of her published work was concerned with spreading medical knowledge. Some of her tracts were written in simple English so that they could easily be understood by those with poor literary skills. She also helped popularise the graphical presentation of statistical data. Much of her writing, including her extensive work on religion and mysticism, has only been published posthumously.
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=68-vsJhcosg</video> 
  <achievements>
		Florence Nightingale's achievements as a nurse and activist in sanitation were a major turning point in the history of health care. Before Miss Nightingale,nurses were either poor servant-class workers, or Roman Catholic nuns. Nurses were usually uneducated in medicine, and did not have much experience in the field. Florence started the Florence Nightingale School of Nursing, she felt all nurses should be well educated. Nightingale helped to break down class barriers, by allowing members of all classes into her school. Before Florence, most hospitals were dirty and poorly planned buildings. Florence's observation, that cleanliness decreased the death rate influenced others to impose sanitation requirements. Florence Nightingale had a major impact on the development of medicine by changing the way nurses were viewed and creating higher sanitary standards for hospitals. 
		
		Florence Nightingale became very involved with the Crimean War in November 1854 when she was asked to assist doctors in the Barrack Hospital. Nightingale brought 38 of the most qualified nurses, mostly well educated nuns, when she accepted the opportunity. Nightingale's goals for her trip were to help the soldiers, and give nurses a better reputation. When Florence first arrived in Turkey the hospitals were dirty, and overcrowded. Nightingale cleaned up the hospitals, made a more pleasing atmosphere for the patients and cleaned the fresh water pipes. Florence's involvement in the war was truly a turning point in the way Europe viewed nurses. The media was very interested in Nightingale's work in the hospitals and during this time. Nightingale became a famous female nurse and the social status of all nurses was improved.
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
 <item>
  <id>2</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Rani Lakshmibai</name>
  <img>ranijhansi</img>
   <bdate>November 19, 1828, Varanasi, India</bdate>
  <ddate>June 18, 1858, Gwalior</ddate>  
  <audio></audio>
  <quote></quote>
  <info>Lakshmibai, The Rani Queen of Jhansi 19 November 1835 – 17 June 1858  known as Jhansi Ki Rani, was the queen of the Maratha-ruled princely state of Jhansi, was one of the leading figures of the Indian Rebellion of 1857, and a symbol of resistance to British rule in India. She has gone down in Indian history as a legendary figure, as India's "Joan of Arc. she was called by the name Manikarnika. Affectionately, her family members called her Manu. At a tender age of four, she lost her mother. As a result, the responsibility of raising her fell upon her father. While pursuing studies, she also took formal training in martial arts, which included horse riding, shooting and fencing. To know the complete life history of Rani Laxmibai of Jhansi, read on
		Originally named Manikarnika at birth nicknamed Manu  , she was born on 19 November 1835 at Kashi Varanasi to a Maharashtrian Karhade Brahmin family from Dwadashi, District Satara. She lost her mother at the age of four. She was educated at home. Her father Moropant Tambey worked at the court of Peshwa Baji Rao II at Bithur and then travelled to the court of Raja Gangadhar Rao Newalkar, the Maharaja of Jhansi, when Manu was thirteen years old. She was married to Gangadhar Rao, the Raja of Jhansi, at the age of 14.

		During that period, Lord Dalhousie was the Governor General of British India. The adopted child was named Damodar Rao. As per the Hindu tradition, he was their legal heir. However, the British rulers refused to accept him as the legal heir. As per the Doctrine of Lapse, Lord Dalhousie decided to seize the state of Jhansi. Rani Lakshmibai went to a British lawyer and consulted him. Thereafter, she filed an appeal for the hearing of her case in London. But, her plea was rejected. The British authorities confiscated the state jewels. Also, an order was passed asking the Rani to leave Jhansi fort and move to the Rani Mahal in Jhansi. Laxmibai was firm about protecting the state of Jhansi
		After her marriage, she was given the name Lakshmi Bai. Because of her father's influence at court, Rani Lakshmi Bai had more independence than most women, who were normally restricted to the zenana: she studied self defense, horsemanship, archery, and even formed her own army out of her female friends at court.
		Rani Lakshmi Bai gave birth to a son in 1851, however this child died when he was about four months old. After the death of their son, the Raja and Rani of Jhansi adopted Damodar Rao. However, it is said that her husband the Raja never recovered from his son's death, and he died on 21 November 1853 of a broken heart.

		Because Damodar Rao was adopted and not biologically related to the Raja, the East India Company, under Governor-General Lord Dalhousie, was able to install the Doctrine of Lapse, rejecting Rao's rightful claim to the throne. Dalhousie then annexed Jhansi, saying that the throne had become "lapsed" and thus put Jhansi under his "protection". In March 1854, the Rani was given a pension of 60,000 rupees and ordered to leave the palace at the Jhansi fort.
  
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m54M0HlECOE</video> 
  <achievements>
		Of all the characters in the epic mutiny of 1857; 150 years later there is one name which stands tall over all others and yet ironically was one who was neither the initiator of the mutiny; neither among the leaders until the last stage. Yet, in many ways she was alone in her magnificence, a singular figure among a gallery of heroes. [1] She was Lakshmi Bai; and that small town immortalized forever is Jhansi. 
		
		Jhansi is a small town in the province of Uttar Pradesh, part of the region known as Bundelkhand. The town still feels that it owes its fame to the young Rani; who ruled for barely four and half years. It keeps alive the memory of its beloved Rani with her image on horseback imprinted all over; at crossroads; on hoardings; in parks her ubiquity conforming what people believe. 
  
		Because of her bravery, courage, and wisdom, and her progressive views on women's empowerment in 19th century India, and due to her sacrifices, she became an icon of Indian independence movement. The Rani was memorialized in bronze statues at both Jhansi and Gwalior, both of which portray her on horseback.  Her story became a beacon for the upcoming generations of freedom fighters. 

		Lot of literature has been written on the life history of Rani Lakshmibai of Jhansi. Heroic poems have been composed in her honor.

  </achievements>
 </item>
 

  <item>
  <id>3</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Annie Besant</name>
  <img>anniebesant</img>
  <bdate>October 1, 1847, Clapham, London, United Kingdom</bdate>
  <ddate>September 20, 1933, Adyar</ddate>  
<!--   <audio>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/the-voice-of-florence-nightingale/</audio> -->
<audio></audio>
  <quote>Better remain silent, better not even think, if you are not prepared to act.
  </quote>
  <info>
 		Annie Besant was a prominent British socialist, theosophist, women's rights activist, writer and orator and supporter of Irish and Indian self-rule.

		At age 20 she married Frank Besant, but separated from him over religious differences. She then became a prominent speaker for the National Secular Society (NSS) and writer and a close friend of Charles Bradlaugh. In 1877 they were prosecuted for publishing a book by birth control campaigner Charles Knowlton. The scandal made them famous, and Bradlaugh was elected M.P. for Northampton in 1880.

		She became involved with union actions including the Bloody Sunday demonstration and the London matchgirls strike of 1888. She was a leading speaker for the Fabian Society and the Marxist Social Democratic Federation (SDF). She was elected to the London School Board for Tower Hamlets, topping the poll even though few women were qualified to vote at that time.

		In 1890 Besant met Helena Blavatsky and over the next few years her interest in theosophy grew while her interest in secular matters waned. She became a member of the Theosophical Society and a prominent lecturer on the subject. As part of her theosophy-related work, she travelled to India. In 1898 she helped establish the Central Hindu College and in 1922 she helped establish the Hyderabad (Sind) National Collegiate Board in Mumbai, India. In 1902, she established the first overseas Lodge of the International Order of Co-Freemasonry, Le Droit Humain. Over the next few years she established lodges in many parts of the British Empire. In 1907 she became president of the Theosophical Society, whose international headquarters were in Adyar, Madras, (Chennai).

		She also became involved in politics in India, joining the Indian National Congress. When World War I broke out in 1914, she helped launch the Home Rule League to campaign for democracy in India and dominion status within the Empire. This led to her election as president of the India National Congress in late 1917. After the war, she continued to campaign for Indian independence and for the causes of theosophy, until her death in 1933.

  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d7_73uXRxYI</video> 
  <achievements>
		President of Theosophical Society of India; founded Home Rule League in 1916 and demand self rule in India; became first woman president of Indian National Congress.

		Annie Besant was a prominent Theosophist, social reformer, political leader, women's rights activist, writer and orator. She was of Irish origin and made India her second home. She fought for the rights of Indian and was the first woman president of Indian National Congress.

  </achievements>
  
 </item>
 
  <item>
  <id>4</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Sarojini Naidu</name>
  <img>sarojininaidu</img>
  <bdate> February 13, 1879, Hyderabad, India</bdate>
  <ddate>March 2, 1949, Lucknow, India</ddate>  
<!--   <audio>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/the-voice-of-florence-nightingale/</audio> -->
<audio></audio>
  <quote>We want deeper sincerity of motive, a greater courage in speech and earnestness in action.
  </quote>
  <info>Sarojini Naidu was an India political leader born on February 13, 1879 in Hyderabad, India. At a young age she wrote poetry and plays, a hobby she kept throughout her life. She later studied in England, and in 1916 she met Mahatma Gandhi which sparked her interest in the fight for India’s freedom. In 1925 she was elected as the first female President of the India National Congress. After India’s independence from England, Naidu became the first woman Governor of Uttar Pradesh. Naidu died on March 02, 1949 at Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh.
  </info>
  <video>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3jpJx0KmF3k</video> 
  <achievements>
		Sarojini Naidu was a distinguished poet, renowned freedom fighter and one of the great orators of her time. She was famously known as Bharatiya Kokila (The Nightingale of India). Sarojini Naidu was the first Indian woman to become the President of the Indian National Congress and the first woman to become the governor of a state in India.
		
		She was the first Indian woman to become the President of the Indian National Congress and the first woman to become the governor of a state in India.
		
		Sarojini Naidu was truly one of the gems of the 20th century India. She was known by the sobriquet "The Nightingale of India". Her contribution was not confined to the fields of politics only but she was also a renowned poet. The play "Maher Muneer", written by Naidu at an early age, fetched a scholarship to study abroad. She briefed the struggles of freedom for independence to the political stalwarts of European nations, she had visited. She married Dr. Muthyala Govindarajulu Naidu, a South India. The marriage took place at a time when inter-caste marriage was not acceptable in the society. Her acts helped in raising many eyebrows. In 1905, a collection of poems, she had composed, was published under the title of "Golden Threshold". 
  
  </achievements>
 </item>
 
  
  
  <item>
  <id>5</id>
  <type>Women\'s History</type>
  <name>Benazir Bhutto</name>
  <img>benazir</img>
  <bdate>June 21, 1953, Karachi, Pakistan</bdate>
  <ddate>December 27, 2007, Rawalpindi, Pakistan</ddate>  
<!--   <audio>http://publicdomainreview.org/collections/the-voice-of-florence-nightingale/</audio> -->
<audio></audio>
  <quote>Democracy is necessary to peace and to undermining the forces of terrorism.
  </quote>
  <info>
		Benazir Bhutto was a Pakistani politician and stateswoman who served as the 11th Prime Minister of Pakistan for two non-consecutive terms from 1988 to 1990 and then from 1993 to 1996. A scion of the politically powerful Bhutto family, she was the eldest daughter of Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, a former prime minister himself who founded the centre-left, social-democratic Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP). She holds the status of being the first female leader of a Muslim country.

		In 1982, three years after her father's assassination, 29-year-old Benazir Bhutto became the chairperson of the PPP—a political party, making her the first woman in Pakistan to head a major political party. In 1988, she became the first woman to be elected as the head of an Islamic state's government; she also remains Pakistan's only female prime minister. Noted for her charismatic authority and political astuteness, Bhutto drove initiatives for Pakistan's economy and national security, and she implemented social-capitalist policies for industrial development and growth. In addition, her political philosophy and economic policies emphasised deregulation (particularly of the financial sector), flexible labour markets, the denationalisation of state-owned corporations, and the withdrawal of subsidies to others. Bhutto's popularity waned amid recession, corruption, and high unemployment which later led to the dismissal of her government by conservative President Ghulam Ishaq Khan.

		In 1993, Bhutto was elected for a second term after the 1993 parliamentary elections. She survived an attempted coup d'état in 1995, and her hard line against the trade unions and tough rhetorical opposition to her domestic political rivals and to neighbouring India earned her the nickname "Iron Lady"; she was also respectfully referred to as "BB". In 1996, charges of corruption levelled against her led to the final dismissal of her government by President Farooq Leghari. Bhutto conceded her defeat in the 1997 Parliamentary elections and went into exile in Dubai in 1999.

		Nine years later, in 2007, she returned to Pakistan, having reached an understanding with President Pervez Musharraf, who granted her amnesty and withdrew all corruption charges against her. Bhutto was assassinated in a bombing on 27 December 2007, after leaving PPP's last rally in Rawalpindi, two weeks before the scheduled 2008 general election in which she was a leading opposition candidate. She is the recipient of United Nations Prize in the Field of Human Rights, Legion of Honour, Order of Ouissam Alaouite and has been submitted into the Academy of Achievement.
  
  </info>
  <video>http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fOHYdajmtp4</video> 
  <achievements>
		She was a chair the Pakistan Peoples Party (PPP), having twice been Prime Minister of Pakistan (19-Oct-1993 to 5-Nov-1996), (9-Dec-1988 to 6-Aug-1990).
		
		She was also the wife of current Pakistani President Asif Ali Zardari.
		
		In 1979 she returned to Pakistan after completing her studies and led the political opposition to President General  Zia-ul-Haq after the execution of her father, Zulfikar Ali Bhutto.  
		
		She subsequently endured frequent house arrest (1979 – 1984). 
		
		Having been allowed in 1984 to return to the United Kingdom, she became a leader in exile of the PPP, her father's party. 
		
		On 16 November 1988, in the first open election in more than a decade,  PPP won and  Bhutto became Prime Minister.
		
		On  December 2 1988 , at age 35 she became the youngest person and the first woman to head the government of a Muslim-majority state in modern times. However she was unable to do much to combat Pakistan's widespread poverty, governmental corruption, and increasing crime. On 6 August 1990  President Ghulam Ishaq Khan charged  her with corruption and misuse of power. She was dismissed from office, while her husband Zardari was arrested. 
		
		In 1993 she was re-elected but her second stint as prime minister (1993 – 96) ended similarly. In 1999 she was convicted of taking kickbacks from a Swiss company and sentenced in absentia to five years in prison. She went into self-imposed exile in Dubai in 1998.
		
		During her work as head of government Bhutto's accomplishments were in initiatives for nationalist reform and modernization, that some conservatives characterized as Westernization.    
		
		Bhutto released political prisoners and took other steps to restore fundamental human rights. Bhutto concerned for women's social and health issues, including the issue of discrimination against women. She also demonstrated considerable skill in winning international diplomatic and economic support for Pakistan
		
		Bhutto returned to Pakistan on 18 October 2007, after reaching an understanding with President Pervez Musharraf by which she was granted amnesty and all corruption charges were withdrawn. Оn 18 October 2007, two explosions occurred shortly after Bhutto had landed and left Jinnah International Airport.
		
		She was not injured but the explosions killed 136 people and injured at least 450. The dead included at least 50 of the security guards. Two month later
		
		she was assassinated while leaving a campaign rally in Rawalpindi on 27 December 2007.
		
		Awards: United Nations Prize in the Field of Human Rights. Prize For Freedom by the Liberal International. (1989), Academy of Achievement (2000),  Phi Beta Kappa Society
  
  </achievements>
 </item>
  
</menu>


